字幕制作: 呆呆@CMCT
怎么回事？
What's going on?
他一定在里面 他不肯开门
He's definitely in there. He aingt opening the door.
- 准备好了吗？- 当然
- You hopped up? - Absolutely.
哈洛？
Harrold?
哈洛
Harrold!
我要跟你谈谈 快开门
Hey, buddy, I wanna talk to you! Open the door!
我听到他在里面
I hear him in there.
哈洛 把手枪掏出来
Harrold! Take your weapons out.
最后一次机会 哈洛
Last chance, Harrold!
靠
Fuck.
去他的
Fucking...
可恶
Shit.
哈洛？哈洛！
Harrold! Harrold?
- 去你的！- 开什么玩笑？
- Fuck! Fuck you! - Fucking kidding me!
你们不能把门踹开吗？
You fucking guys can't kick the fucking door?
- 哈洛 穿上衣服 - 我投降
- Harrold, get some clothes on! - I got my hands up.
- 别向我开枪 - 闭嘴
- Don't fucking shoot me! - Shut up! Hey!
你们光站着干嘛？
What the fuck are you doing? You guys gonna just stand there?
快进去抓他 替他穿上衣服
Go in there and get him! Put some clothes on him!
我什么都没做
I fucking didn't do nothing!
我干嘛踹开大门？
Fuck did I kick that fucking door?
- 局长 - 克里斯 谢了
- Hey, Commish. - Chris.
艾德 戴维斯
三楼
Third floor upstairs.
波士顿警局局长
- 三楼？- 对
- Third? - Yeah.
- 到底发生什么事？- 我只是去
- What happened with "Shan-creek-a"? - I was just going over there
找一个女的
to have an appointment with this female,
另一个女的突然冒出来
and this lady came out of nowhere
用冰沙袭击我
and brained me with a smoothie.
她女儿说你推她
Her daughter says you pushed her.
那只母猪想要逃跑
Sir, I was trying to make an escape...
- 你有没有推她？- 她用冰沙打我以后
- Did you push her? - After the smoothie.
- 你有推她 - 怎么回事 汤米？
- So you did... - What's up, Tommy.
哇塞 警察局长竟然大驾光临
Whoa! This is an occasion. Commish exiting the SUV?
- 这是杀人案件吗？- 不是 你接到误报
- Is this a homicide? - It's not. You've been misinformed.
别开玩笑 这不是杀人案？
You're fucking kidding me. It's not a homicide?
- 不是 - 不是啦 长官
- Nope. - No, sir. No, sir.
- 你为什么在流血？- 我正在告诉警官
- Why are you bleeding? - I was trying to tell your officers, sir.
这女人疯了
This woman is crazy.
她用冰沙打我的头
And she hit me with a fucking smoothie in the head.
什么冰沙？那种饮料吗？
What are you talking about? Like, a drink or something?
不是啦 是冰沙
No, like a fucking smoothie, you know?
用来弄平衣服的东东
Like you would smooth your clothes out with.
- 熨斗？一个熨斗？- 熨斗
- An iron? A fucking iron? - An iron!
- 真是够了 - 那个东东叫熨斗
- For fuck's sake! - It's called an iron, Harrold.
- 对 冰沙 - 闭嘴
- Yes, sir, a smoothie. - Shut up.
我早该当上警监 副总警监…
Commish, I should be a captain or a deputy-super
或是局长
or probably even your job by now.
我受不了这种鸟事了
I can't take much more of this shit.
这是你自找的
You dug that hole.
我的膝盖真痛
You know, my fucking knee is killing me.
他踢爆一个扫黄组警探的牙齿…
He kicked the fucking teeth out of a vice cop in Back Bay.
你怎么会把自己的膝盖踢伤？
How do you fuck your knee up kicking a guy in the mouth?
我太用力了啦
I over-kicked. I hyper-extended it.
我以为他会被停职
I thought he fucking got suspended.
喂 我可听到了 猪头
Hey! I fucking hear you, numb-nuts.
- 对不起 我是听说的 - 你听说什么？
- Sorry, that's what I heard. - What'd you hear?
- 我听说你被停职了 - 我看起来像被停职吗？
- I heard that you got suspended. - Do I look suspended?
- 不像 长官 - 他不像被停职
- No, sir. - He doesn't look suspended.
我被停职还能盯着你们看吗？
Would I be sitting here staring at you two chowderheads if I was suspended?
当然不能 人生本来就不公平
No, I wouldn't. Life is a rigged fucking game.
你们最好学乖一点 别送命
You two just passed "Go." Buckle it the fuck up.
- 哈洛 你被捕了 - 一点也没错
- Harrold, you're under arrest. - Actually accurate.
回家拿冰敷下膝盖 睡个好觉
You go home, put some ice on that knee, and get some sleep.
- 五小时后就是马拉松赛 - 我又得抓酒鬼
- Got the race in five hours. - Catching drunks at the marathon.
拜托别逼我穿黄色的小丑衣
Boss, please, don't make me wear the clown suit.
这是最后一次 带着微笑值勤
It's the last hoop, Tommy.
然后你就能正式复职
You walk your beat, smile, and you're officially out of the doghouse.
再撑一天
One more day.
天气会很好 又有正妹 就像是野餐
Weather's gonna be nice, pretty girls, fresh air, be like a big picnic.
大家都爱野餐
Everybody loves a picnic.
晚10:16
肯斯基与道恩斯家
- 派屈克的披萨快递 - 嗨 宝贝
- Pizza delivery for Patrick. - Hey, baby.
工作如何？
Hey. How was work?
有一位好心的老人家给我这个
This sweet old man came in and gave that to me today.
范先生
Mr. Flanagan.
他太太两个月前 住在我值班的病房
His wife was on my floor a couple months back.
四期癌症！我们只能给她安宁照顾
Stage four, so we were just there to keep her comfortable.
我猜她在走之前 让他把项链送给我
I guess before she passed, she told him she wanted me to have it.
我跟他们一点都不熟 但…
I hardly knew them,
他人超好又很伤心
but he was so sweet and so sad,
我只能抱着他 安慰他
and I was just holding him and hugging him.
这条项链真漂亮
Look at how pretty that is.
很美 对吧？
Isn't that beautiful?
你替我带了晚餐？
And you made me dinner?
你的论文写得怎样？
How's your dissertation coming?
写了两段 全都删掉了
Two paragraphs, both deleted.
不过我找到旧金山的公寓要给你看
And, uh, but I did tag some cool apartments in San Francisco to show you.
- 真的吗？- 真的
- Yeah? - Yeah.
- 看吧你给乐的 - 我是很高兴
- Look at you, so excited. - Well, I'm really excited
因为我们明天要放假呀
that we're taking the day off tomorrow.
我在想…吃了这么多披萨
And I think after my masterpiece pizza,
我们应该要跑跑步
we're gonna have to go on a run at some point.
- 明天？不 - 对
- Tomorrow? No, honey. - Yeah.
你在爱国者日可以做三件事
There's three things you can do on Patriots Day.
看马拉松赛 跑马拉松
One's watch the marathon, the other one's run the marathon,
或是到芬威球场 向红袜队大吼大叫
and the third one is get down to Fenway and yell for those Red Sox.
- 向红蛙队大吼大叫 - 红袜队
- Yelling for the Red Sox. - Sox.
- 红蛙队 - 红袜队
- Sox. - Mmm. Red "Sahx."
- 红袜队 - 红袜队
- Red "Sahx." - Red "Sahx."
- 这就对了 - 我觉得你只想
- There you go. - I think you just wanna stay
跟我窝在床上一整天
in bed with me all day.
你知道我怎么想吗？
Wanna know what I think?
范太太把项链送给你 是因为…
I think the reason Mrs. Flanagan wanted you to have it
她知道你会抱着范先生安慰他
was because she knew you would hold him when he gave it to you.
你真是个好男人
You're a very sweet man.
我知道 干杯
I know. Cheers.
敬红蛙队
To the Red Sox.
红袜队
Yeah. "Sahx."
- 红蛙队 - 红袜队
- Sox. - "Sahx."
红袜队
"Sahx."
晚11:28
麻省理工学院
你换了软件吗？
Did you change the software and shit?
好吧 让我们看看
All right, let's see.
好 行了
Uh, yeah. Got it.
好耶
Yes!
自主性跳跃
- 嗨 小李 - 嗨 尚恩 怎么样？
- Hey, Li. What's up, guys? - Oh, hey, Sean, what's up?
哇 你都喂那玩意吃什么？
Wow! What are you feeding that thing?
他跑得比巡逻警车还快
It looks like he could outrun the squad car.
- "她"看起来不太妙 - 快看
- She definitely could. - Look at this!
- 我能摸吗？- 不行
- Can I touch it? - No.
不行
No. No.
柴克牛仔演唱会怎么样？
So what about the Zac cowboy concert?
- 柴克布朗乐团 - 对
- Zac Brown Band, yeah. - Yeah.
我会买十张票
Yeah, I'll get ten tickets.
那会是一次文化体验
Hey, it's gonna be a cultural experience, okay?
比在麻省理工 哈佛念书 更有教育意义
You're gonna get a better education than MIT, Harvard, BU, BC.
大家都会拿到免费帽子
I need everybody's hat sizes, we'll all get hats.
- 太棒了 - 我马上回来
- Yeah, cool. - Get right.
- 好吧 - 谢了
- All right, boys. - Thanks.
你知道我周五夜最爱吃炸鸡…
Well, listen, you know I like my chicken fried,
- 还有喝冰啤酒 - 我也是
- a cold beer on a Friday night... - Me, too.
然后穿紧身牛仔裤
and my jeans that fit too tight.
- 很合身 - 那就好
- Just right. Your jeans, just right. - Just right. Just right.
你想你…一定会去吗？
Do you think you'll definitely come?
- 会啦 - 我一定会去
- Or... - Yes. I will be there.
太好了
Okay. Cool. Yeah.
晚12:55
桑德斯家
汤米
Oh, Tommy!
对不起 我得拿明天的制服
I'm sorry. I just gotta get my clothes for tomorrow.
汤米…滚出我的房间
Tommy, oh, my God. Get the fuck out of my room.
- 这是我们的房间 - 我听你拿钥匙刮门锁的声音
- But this is our room. - You know, now I can officially
就知道你喝了多少
tell your blood alcohol by the frequency of key scratches on the lock.
- 保证没错 汤米 - 我只喝了两杯
- It's a predictive pattern, Tommy. - I had two pops, okay?
用来镇痛 我就要去报到了
It's medicinal. And I got roll call...
- 你很吵 - 再过4小时42分钟…
- You sound like... - ...in four hours and 42 minutes.
- 吵死了 - 对不起
- ...elephant. - I'm sorry. All right?
快滚吧 早上见
Please, come on, just go. I'll see you in the morning.
要我陪你窝着睡觉吗？
Hey... want me to cuddle with you?
- 不要 我叫你快滚 - 来嘛
- No! I told you to leave, Tommy. - Come on.
- 我爱你 - 我爱你
- I love you. - I love you.
- 快滚啦 你把我吵醒了 - 对不起
- Go on. You're waking me up. - I'm sorry. All right?
- 够了 给我闭嘴 - 接着睡吧
- Okay. Quit ya' talking. - Go back to sleep.
2013年4月15日 星期一
爱国者日
上午6:34
马拉松赛前3小时
这部车满好看的吧？
很贵吧？为什么要买这么漂亮的车？
没什么 女孩喜欢好的车嘛
你太忙了 都没有时间交女朋友
没有 我就跟你学的嘛
什么时候你休息了我也休息了 好吗？
你这样肯定睡眠不够啦
儿子 回头再聊
有空再说
上午7:08
沙尼耶夫家
要喝水吗？
You wanna go get your drink?
你不想讲话？口渴啦？
One on top? You thirsty?
好了 来吧
Yeah, let's go. Come on.
你要喝什么？果汁？牛奶？
What do you want? Juice? Milk?
妈咪 妈咪 开开
Mommy, Mommy, open.
给你 宝贝
Here you go, baby.
我们进房间去
Let's go in the room.
制服干了
Uniform's dry.
我还给你的对讲机换了电池
I also swapped out the battery in your shoulder mic.
我好久没看你穿制服了
I haven't seen you in your uniform for a while.
我是故意不穿的
Yeah, that was on purpose.
- 天啊 来 - 让我看看
- Oh, God. - Come on. Let me see it.
- 别闹啦 - 这让我有点兴奋
- Don't start. - Mmm. Kinda turns me on.
- 真的吗？- 你得先剪头发
- Really? - Gotta get your hair cut first.
那是我的第一要务
It's at the top of my list.
我超讨厌穿制服
God, I gotta put this thing on.
我像个小丑吗？
Do I look like a clown?
- 你在笑什么？- 没有呀
- Why are you laughing? - I'm not.
- 我像个小丑 没关系 - 没啦 只是…
- I look like a clown. - No! It's just...
- 还不错吧 - 颜色太艳了
- No, it's okay. - It's your color.
我简直就像个导护妈妈
I'm basically a crossing guard, all right?
他们派我到马拉松的终点线
And they send me to the Marathon, at the finish line
大人物都在那里 大家都会笑我
with the biggest VIPs in the city, and everybody's gonna break my balls.
我的哨子和旗子呢？
You got my whistle and my stop sign?
过来 亲我一下
Come here. Gimme a kiss.
- 我爱你 - 我爱你
- I love you. - I love you.
- 晚点见 好吗？- 好
- I'll see you later on, all right? - All right.
今晚见
I'll see you tonight.
别再踢警察了
Don't kick any cops.
- 我会试着忍住 - 听说他们会不爽
- I'll try not to. - I hear they hate that.
水镇
波士顿以西7英里
上午7:54
普格列斯家
亲爱的？昨天你有看到我吗？
Sweetheart? You saw me yesterday, right?
是我在乱想
So, is it just me,
还是我越来越帅了？
or am I getting a little better looking every day?
过来 我会让你知道你有多帅
Why don't you come over here, and I'll show you how good-looking you are?
我也希望我有时间
Boy, I wish I had time for that.
我爱你
Love you.
你要马芬饼 还是贝果面包？
What do you want, a muffin or a bagel?
- 替我带个马芬饼 - 遵命 老婆
- Oh, bring me a muffin, please. - Yes, doll.
- 我爱你 - 我也爱你
- Love you! - Love you!
- 嗨 蒂莎 - 早安 杰夫警长
- Hey, Tiesha. - Morning, Sergeant Jeff.
- 今天要什么？- 今天要马芬 亲爱的
- How's your day today? - It is a muffin day, sweetheart.
- 今天有蓝莓马芬 - 你真是个天使
- We got blueberry. - Oh. You're an angel.
- 我是你的专属天使 - 书念得怎样？
- I try to be, just for you. - How's school going?
你儿子没有吵你看书吧？
The boys leaving you alone, letting you study?
没有 他们没办法
They are. They have no choice.
你的小费
In the cup.
- 祝你愉快 - 你也是
- Have a great day. - You, too.
这里…桌子旁边
Right over there, next to the table.
起点
要放另一支影片 还是没时间了？
Are we feeding that other video or no time to?
2013年波士顿马拉松
上午8:42
马拉松赛终点线
有证件的人
Nobody in the VIP section at all.
才能进贵宾区 懂吗？
Unless they have credentials, period, all right?
嘿 汤米
Hey, Tommy!
- 什么事？- 我要请你帮个忙
- What's up? - I got a favor.
其实是我帮你 你要去终点线
It's actually a gift. I'm gonna give you the finishing line.
- 拜托 - 别抱怨
- Come on! - No, no, no.
比利艾文斯
这算是欢迎你回来 不准搞砸
This is your welcome back, Tommy. Means no more fuck-ups.
波士顿警局总警监
你只要对着贵宾微笑就成了
Just smile in front of all the VIPs
让他们记住 汤米桑德斯有多帅
and let 'em all remember what a great fucking guy Tommy Saunders is.
- 知道了 我能跟你谈谈吗？- 不行
- I understand that. Can I just talk to you for a second? - No, no, no, no.
你只要说声"谢谢你"
Look, can't you see the beauty of just saying "Thank you"?
然后我说声"不客气"
I say, "You're welcome." Huh?
你就能复职
It's just a trade-off to get your job back.
听我说…
Look...
别再说了 我得赶去起点了
No more words. I just wanna get to the Hopkinton, all right?
- 你会跑多久？- 希望3小时内跑完
- What time you gonna run? - Under three, I hope.
不可能 祝你好运
That aren't happening. Good luck.
你看什么看？
What are you looking at?
全世界薪水最高的交通警察
World's most overpaid meter maid.
把路障移开 我得赶去起点
You wanna move the barricades? I gotta get to Hopkinton.
别光站着 他叫你们把路障移开
Hey! Well, don't stand around. He told you to move the barricade, not me.
卡萝 帮我个忙
Carol! I need you to do me a favor.
我的膝盖更肿了
My knee's gotten swollen fatter.
替我拿个大一号的护膝
I gotta have you bring the fatter knee brace down to me, all right?
然后到终点线找我
I'm at the finish line, so you'll be able to find me.
我爱你 谢了
All right, I love you, baby. Thanks.
那么
Yeah, but what about, like-like,
艾瑞克 拉斐和布兰登他们呢
Erik and Rafi and Brendan and those guys?
他们以前是我们的朋友…
I mean, those guys were our friends, so it's like...
想都别想 无所谓
Don't think about 'em. Doesn't matter.
老哥 我并不是害怕想要退出
Bro, I'm... Look, I'm not pussing out or nothing.
我只是想到马丁路德金
I'm not at all. I'm just thinking about Martin Luther King, and like...
马丁路德金 又不是穆斯林
Martin Luther King was not a Muslim.
他是个伪君子和滥交者
He was a hypocrite. He was a fornicator.
我也是滥交者呀
Yeah, but I'm a fornicator.
你觉得这很好笑吗？
You think that's funny?
没有啊
No.
过来
Come here.
干嘛？
What?
- 干嘛啦？- 你是我兄弟
- What? - You're my brother.
- 懂吗？- 懂啦
- You understand that? - Yeah.
- 你准备好了吗？- 好了
- Are you ready for this? - Yeah.
早上好
Good morning, everyone.
欢迎收看波士顿马拉松直播
It is great to have you with us for the running of the Boston Marathon.
第一轮将于10分钟后开跑
Round one starts in ten minutes.
这里是位于霍普金顿的起点
We're looking at a live picture of the start line
上午9:46
霍普金顿起跑线
参赛者即将从这里起跑
in Hopkinton where it all begins for the runners...
比利艾文斯总警监
Superintendent Billy Evans
代表波士顿警局参赛
representing the Boston Police Department.
还有30秒起跑
30 seconds to go. This will...
世界级马拉松好手 勒利萨戴西沙
There is Lelisa Desisa, who I think is probably the...
为了纪念26名
In remembrance of the 20 students
不幸丧命的师生
and six staff members who lost their lives,
波士顿田径协会
the Boston Athletic Association
谨向纽敦镇镇民
wishes to express its deepest sympathy
以及受害者家属致以最深切的同情
to the families of the victims of all residents of Newtown.
我谨代表大会
We ask that you join us in observing
- 敬请各位 - A准备
- a period of silence... - Standby, A.
- 默哀26秒钟 - C就绪
- ...of 26 seconds. - Ready, C.
C就位
Ready C is up.
26…25…24
Twenty-six, 25, 24,
23…22…
23, 22,
21…20…
21, 20,
19…18…
19, 18,
17…16…15…
17, 16, 15,
14…13…12…
14, 13, 12,
11…10…9…
11, ten, nine,
8…7…
eight, seven,
6…5…
six, five...
4…3…2…1…
4, 3, 2, 1...
出发了
And they are off.
第117届波士顿马拉松赛 专业男子组起跑了
The elite men in the 117th running of the Boston Marathon,
这是美国历史最悠久的马拉松比赛
the oldest running marathon in the United States.
位于霍普金顿的起跑路线…
You can see that the crowd has thickened to about four deep
现在已经挤满了运动员
at some places there along this course in Hopkinton...
上午10:17
柯利尔家
哇 你们用夜视模式？
Donohue, are you on night vision?
为什么开夜视模式？这算作弊
Why are you on night vision? That's atrocious.
这家伙欠我20块
And this guy owes me 20 bucks.
别乱碰 我怎么会欠你20块？
Watch your hand, man. And what do I owe you $20 for again?
- 因为我跟她讲话了 - 你才没有呢
- 'Cause I talked to her. - You didn't talk to her.
少来 你跟她讲话了？
Get the fuck outta here. You talked to her?
她说她要去柴克布朗乐团演唱会
She said she's coming to the Zac Brown concert.
- 你犯了大错 - 她是MIT的高材生
- Big mistake. - Nice MIT girl?
她一定会很喜欢
She'll love it. She'll be smitten.
你应该带她去听波士顿大众管弦乐团
Gotta take her to something classy, like the Pops.
- 大众管弦乐团？- 没错
- The Pops? - Yeah, the Pops.
- 你能说上一个古典乐大师 - 贝多芬 搞定
- Name one Pop. - Beethoven. Done.
冲进谷仓 包抄他
Go to the barn! Flank him, flank him!
老爹农庄好去处…装货 跑路
∮Pop's farm was the place to go, load the truck up, hit the dirt road∮
翻墙 传话…
∮Jump the barbwire, spread the word ∮
点火 把妹
∮Light the bonfire, then call the girls ∮
啤酒香烟…
∮King in the can and the Marlboro Man ∮
好友相陪
∮Jack and Jim were a few good men ∮
顺便学会骂人和打架
∮When we learned how to kiss and cuss and fight, too∮
最好小心警察伯伯
∮Better watch out for the boys in blue ∮
悠闲站在乡间小路
∮Chilling on a dirt road ∮
拦在中间等着抓人
∮Laid back, swerving like I'm George Jones ∮
- 快丢闪光弹 - 搞定
- Throw the flash bang! Throw... - Got it!
- 你每次都来这招 - 你挡住电视了
- You do this every time! - You're in the way of the TV!
拿来啦
Give me the fucking...
他一路狂飙 差点撞倒摄影车
took off so fast that he almost caught the camera truck.
从霍普金顿出来
on a course that stretches from Hopkinton
一路经过亚什兰 弗雷明 罕纳提克…
through Ashland, Framingham, Natick...
戴西沙在荧幕的右侧
Desisa's to the right of your screen...
画面转到女子组 她们跑到6英里处
back to the women for a second, they got about six miles...
跑者到达8英里处
The elites have reached mile eight.
即将经过波尔斯顿街
Expected on Boylston Street...
我得回馈社会
Paying my debt to society.
- 天啊 - 被打入冷宫了？
- Oh, God... - In the doghouse, huh?
没事
Yeah, but it's all right.
只要过了这一关就妥当了
He says it's the last hoop, so we'll see.
剪个头发吧
Get a haircut, though, will ya?
你不剃腿毛我就剪
I'll cut my hair once you stop shaving your legs.
上午11:08
东剑桥
抱歉 我找不到外套了
Sorry! Couldn't find my jacket.
准备走了吗？
Ready to go?
- 能不能先买点喝的？- 好啊
- Can we grab some drinks before we go? - Sure.
- 我想喝酒 - 没问题
- Let's get "drunch." - You don't have to beg me.
参赛者都到了
and as all the contenders are in there,
对领头的运动员紧追不舍
and they're closing hand over fist.
柯戈 戴西沙 葛布雷马里安
Kogo, Desisa, and Gabremariam.
有两位都是埃塞俄比亚选手
So Ethiopia has two of the three.
- 准备好了吗？- 好了
- Ready, man? - Yes, Daddy.
- 真的吗？- 真的
- You are? - Yeah.
- 你想去看妈妈？- 对
- Wanna go see Mommy at the race? - Yeah!
你想替妈妈加油？
Wanna go cheer on Mommy at the race?
那就走吧 走吧
Let's roll. Let's roll.
好吧
All right.
很好
Yes.
跑过波士顿最著名的街道
and running one of the most famous streets in Boston...
领先者到达23英里处
The front-runners are approaching mile 23!
2013年波士顿马拉松大赛
We're mere minutes away from crowning the winner
- 冠军即将揭晓 - 人太多了 赶一些走
- of the 2013 Boston Marathon. - Get some people outta here.
这不符合消防规定 人太多了
This is against fire code. We got way too many people.
- 她可以留下来 - 谢了 汤米
- She can stay. - Thanks, Tommy.
你好吗？你先生呢？
How are you? How's your husband, good?
他很好
He's good. He's doing fine.
镜头转到心碎山坡
Again, you're looking at Heartbreak Hill now.
我们暂时离开专业组
We're leaving the elites now.
肯莫尔广场…
Kenmore Square.
我们看到屋顶的灯光塔
You see the light stanchions over that building.
波士顿最著名的景点
This is one of the really cool spots in Boston...
瞧吧 波士顿马拉松
And look at that, the Boston Marathon running
运动员们经过芬威球场
right past Fenway Park, which will soon empty out...
右转后就会跑向波尔斯顿街
making the right turn, they're heading up towards Boylston.
看来埃塞俄比亚选手即将赢得冠军
Looks like Ethiopia is gonna reign supreme!
他们来了
And here they come!
只剩最后一个街区
Heading down Boylston for the last block!
街上还有别人吗？
Is there anyone else on the road?
他跑得非常快
Very fast time.
保持住 3号摄像机
Standby, camera three..
三 二 一
Three, two, one...
开始引路
and lead the way.
戴西沙是2013年…
Desisa is the 2013
专业男子组冠军
champion of the elites.
波士顿警局
这才是波士顿马拉松真正的精神
Time to take in what the Boston Marathon is truly about.
看着成千上万名业余选手完成比赛
Watching thousands of amateur athletes complete the amazing feat.
你最好脱掉洋基队棒球帽
I'd think about losing that Yankees cap.
酒吧全是红袜队迷 小心挨揍
You got a lot of Sox fans in these bars. I'd hate to see ya get tuned up.
欢迎 弗兰克奈特 来自马赛诸塞州 波士顿
And say hello to Frank Night, from Boston, Massachusetts.
谢谢
Thanks.
不好意思
Excuse me. Sorry. Sorry 'bout that.
借过 对不起
Please excuse me.
比利艾文斯总警监 冲过终点线
That's Police Chief Billy Evans crossing the finish line!
好样的 比利
Way to go, Billy!
- 谢谢你 州长 - 干得好
- Thank you, Governor. - Nice job.
谁有一大坨奶油沾酱？
Does anybody have a big tub of melted butter?
有一只大龙虾跨越终点线
A huge lobster just crossed the finish line!
李欧…
Hey! Leo...
- 暂停 - 我不要暂停
- Time out. - No time out!
- 嗨 - 老婆
- Hey! - Baby...
- 你有没有乖乖的呀？- 当然有
- You behaving yourself? - Oh, yeah.
拿去 护膝
Here it is, you numbskull.
你戴错护膝站了一整天？
You're on your feet all day, and you wear the wrong one?
这样你才会来呀
I did it on purpose so you'd have to bring me the fatter one.
- 很浪漫吧？- 你敢肯定 你是故意的
- Romantic, right? - I'm sure that was your plan!
- 陪我走走 - 我得回去上班
- You wanna walk with me a bit? - No, I gotta get back to work!
我还得挤出去
I gotta claw my way outta this zoo!
- 我爱你 谢了 - 我也爱你
- I love you. Thanks for the brace. - I love you, too.
把这个给乔伊…
Hey, give that to Joey.
看看博伊尔斯顿街
Looking down Boylston,
运动员们陆续跑向终点线
you can see waves of runners turning the corner for the final...
看到那个家伙吗？
Did you see that guy?
穿着黄背心的巴顿将军
There he is. General Patton in a neon vest.
局长 我会拿着冰沙
Hey, Commish, I'll get a fucking smoothie and be waiting in the back
等着你和老Q
of the Tahoe for you and Q.
喂 抓住那个家伙
Hey, grab this bozo!
把他带走 睁大你们的眼睛
Get him outta here! Keep your eyes open, will ya?
我以你为傲 还好吧？
I'm proud of ya, Tommy. How ya feeling?
膝盖痛 背痛
The knee hurts. The back hurts.
蛋蛋痛 浑身都痛
The balls hurt. The pain sometimes feels
痛上加痛
like it hurts on top of the hurt,
一直会痛下去
if that's even remotely possible.
我是戴维斯
This is Davis.
拜登预计3点来电
No, the Biden call's scheduled for 3:00.
副总统拜登？让我跟他说话
Biden? Vice President Biden? Hey, let me talk to him.
- 别闹了 - 让我跟他说话嘛
- Behave yourself, Tommy. - Commissioner, let me talk to him!
大龙虾又来了
Guys! The lobster's back!
过来 把他铐起来
Come here! Cuff that lobster, will you?
轮椅组的决赛选手来了
The finalists in the wheelchair competition here...
在这著名的过程中 产生过很多飞快的选手
very fast runners here out on this storied course.
这是一场历史悠久的马拉松大赛
So much history today.
我们要向所有的参赛者和工作人员
To all the runners and our team behind the scenes,
致上最高的谢意
thank you for bringing this race...
是炸弹 警监 是炸弹
Those are bombs, Captain! Those are bombs!
这是D984 发生多起爆炸案 需要增援
This is Delta 984! We got multiple explosions! We need...
靠
Shit!
快派医疗人员到终点线 快点
All medical personnel to the finish line! Now!
终点线附近发生爆炸
Something just exploded at the finish line.
他们说什么？快掉头
What did he say? Let's turn around, Q.
重覆 多人伤亡
I repeat, multiple casualties!
有我呢
I got you.
你不会有事 你不会有事
Sir, you're gonna be okay, all right? You're gonna be okay.
用力按住伤口
Ma'am, hold on to this as tight as you can.
快把轮椅推过来
Hey, get that wheelchair over here now!
医疗人员快赶到终点线
All medical personnel to the finish line!
- 我要两辆救护车 - 重复 多人伤亡
- We need two over here! - Repeat, multiple casualties!
- 汤米 - 卡萝
- Tommy! - Carol!
你没事吧？我看看
You okay? Huh? Let me see.
还好 你没事… 萨利 过来
All right. You're okay. You're okay. Hey, Sully, come here!
卡萝 跟他去 送她回家
Carol, go with him now! Get her home now!
重复你的位置
Repeat your location!
这是D984 我在终点线
This is Delta 984! I'm at the finish line!
我只听984警官的指挥
I only wanna hear from the 984!
我只听长官指挥
I only wanna hear from that supervisor.
好的 我就想听这个
All right, this is what I need.
我要清空林恩路 好让救护车进出
I want Ring Road clear, so I can push ambulances in and out!
继续让救护车开进来
Keep pushing in those ambulances!
好 有人来了
Okay. People are coming.
小姐 你着火了 你没事
Ma'am, you're on fire. That's it.
该死
Oh, shit!
警官？
Sir?
赶快找人帮帮我们 拜托
Can we get some help, sir? Anyone, sir, please?
好的
Yeah.
你没事…你没事…劳夫 过来
You're okay. You're okay. Ralph, come here.
你没事
You're okay.
我们得把你儿子带去救助
We gotta take your son and get him some help.
李欧 李欧
Leo! Leo!
你不会有事的
You're gonna be okay, sir.
你还好么？能听到吗？
You all right? You hear me?
你没事
You're okay.
我听不到
I can't...
我们会想办法
We'll figure this out.
- 我会去找你 - 杰丝…
- I'll find you in just a minute. - Jess...
我需要轮椅 快点
Get the wheelchairs! Come on!
她的双腿严重撕裂
Both of her legs are severely lacerated.
- 数到三 预备 - 这是我妻子
- On three, ready? - This is my wife.
她会没事的
She's gonna be okay.
马上派两辆救护车到林恩路
Hey! Send two more ambulances from Ring Road right now!
这是戴维斯警官 在广场咖啡馆
This is Sergeant Davis at the Forum Cafe.
立刻派人搜索爆炸现场
I need personnel at the second bomb site immediately!
我需要协助
I need assistance!
我正赶去第二爆炸现场
This is Delta 984. I'm heading to the second bomb site!
所有人 保持频道畅通
Everybody, keep this line clear!
别再让运动员跑过来 封锁爆炸现场
And stop letting runners through! Secure the perimeter!
再让我看到运动员 你就死定了
If I see another runner, your ass is done!
我们需要救护车
We need a fucking ambulance over here!
第二爆炸现场需要救护车
We need ambulances down at the second bombing site!
星巴克和广场咖啡馆
Starbucks and the Forum!
还有炸弹吗？还有吗？
Are there more bombs? Are there more bombs?
看着我 你不会有事的
No, no, no, no. Look at me. You're gonna be okay.
- 你会好的 - 那是什么？
- You're doing good, all right? - What's that? What's that?
别看 看着我
Don't look at that! Look at me! Look at me!
快把轮椅推过来
Get that over here now!
立刻停止比赛
Guys, shut down the race!
别让任何人跑向波尔斯顿街
Do not have another person run down Boylston Street!
把她抬起来 停止比赛
Come on, get her up, get her up! Shut down the race!
靠 汤米 有两人丧命
Fuck, Tommy! We've got two fatalities.
两人丧命 一个是8岁小孩
We got two fatalities, and a fucking kid, eight years old.
- 他的家人呢？- 受伤了
- Where's his family? - They're wounded.
他们把大家都拖走了
They fucking dragged everybody out.
- 该死 该怎么办？- 我也不知道
- For fuck's sake, what do we do? - I don't fucking know.
有人得陪着他 不能把他丢在这儿
We gotta leave someone with him. We cannot leave him here alone, Captain.
我们得找人陪着他…警员
No, we're gonna get someone by his side.
立即离开这里
out of the area immediately.
我们要清理边界 也许会有更多炸弹
We gotta clear the perimeter. Could be more bombs.
没问题
Yeah, I'm on it.
有人在吗？有人吗？
Anyone in here? Anyone?
该死
Shit!
我们必须没收所有的手机
This is Delta 984. We gotta confiscate all cell phones.
看到有人在用手机就立刻没收
Repeat. If you see anyone recording, grab their phones, I don't care who it is!
你们得找到我儿子
They gotta find my boy.
求求你们
Somebody, please...
放心 我们会找到他
Don't worry. We'll find him, sir.
我不知道他在哪里
I don't know where he is.
下午3:14
马州总医院
我是詹医师 我会照顾你
Lee, I'm James. I'm going to take care of you, all right?
你会没事的
You're going to be fine.
有知觉吗？你能动一动脚趾吗？
Can you feel that? Can you wiggle your toes?
很好 非常好
Good. Good, good, good. We're good.
我们会保住你的腿
We're gonna save your leg, okay?
你们得帮我找到儿子
Hey, you gotta help me find my son.
他叫李欧伍芬顿 3岁大
His name is Leo Woolfenden. He's three years old.
有人带走他 我们分散了
We got separated somehow. Somebody took him.
你们得找到他
I just didn't... You need to find him.
他叫李欧伍芬顿…
His name is Leo Woolfenden. W-O-O-L...
下午3:37
爆炸后47分钟
把人群疏散到封锁区以外
Push out and make sure we're keeping people out of the perimeter.
- 可以吗 快行动 - 我们封锁了六个街区
- All right? Get moving. - We've got a six-block perimeter set up.
我们都封锁了
We're all locked down here.
惨了 他们来了 他们来了
Oh, boy. Here we go. Here we go.
瑞克德洛里耶
联邦调查局 特别探员
德瓦尔派屈克
马萨诸塞州 州长
- 这是第一爆炸现场？- 是的
- This is the first blast scene? - Yeah.
第二爆炸现场在广场咖啡馆
The second was down there at the Forum restaurant.
- 分局全体探员正在赶来 - 我们需要分析爆裂物
- Total station en route. - Okay, we need TEDAC and OPU.
- 手机和监控探头呢？- 我们会马上处理
- What about cell phones, cameras? - Yeah, we're right on top of that.
我们正在搜集手机 视频录像
Yeah, we're collecting cell phones, surveillance tapes,
- 所有的监控头 - 全都要找到 别漏了
- all the video we can find. - Get 'em all, Tommy. Don't miss any.
封锁范围有多大？
How big is the secured perimeter?
六个街区
Six blocks off the course each direction.
- 扩大到十个街区 - 没问题
- Let's extend that. Make it 10. - You got it.
位置很精确 可能有更多炸弹
It's clearly coordinated. There could be more bombs.
- 伤亡人数有多少？- 目前已知三人死亡
- How many total wounded? - Got three fatalities that we know of.
- 其中有一个广场咖啡馆前的儿童 - 他们在干嘛？
- One's a little child on the street in front of the Forum. - What are they doing?
那是个8岁的小孩
What? I said that's an eight-year-old kid under there.
不准动尸体 请他们让开
No, they can't move the body. We've gotta clear them out.
请他们马上离开
Tell them to clear out of there!
- 没问题 - 请他们马上离开
- You got it, you got it. - Tell them to clear out of there.
- 你是什么人？- 抱歉 警官
- Who the fuck are you? - Sorry, Sergeant.
孩子身上的血迹可能有…炸弹残留物
Could be clues in the blood-splattered bomb residue on the boy's body.
我们不能冒险 绝对不能移动尸体
We can't risk moving him. Nothing moves.
你们是没心没肺吗？你想告诉孩子的父母
What's the matter with you guys? You gonna tell that boy's parents
孩子还躺在马路上
that their son's still lying on the fucking street?
- 冷静点 - 去你的
- Turn it down, Tommy. - Oh, fuck that!
- 汤米 过去 - 好吧 比利
- Tommy! Let's go over there. - All right, Billy...
别管我 好吗？
Just fucking leave me alone, will ya?
我们得赶快决定 谁来指挥调查行动
We've gotta decide who's running this, and we have to decide quickly.
若是恐怖行动 就由你指挥
If it's terrorism, it's yours, Rick.
一旦定位为恐袭 事情就严重了
Gentlemen, the moment we label this terrorism, everything changes.
这不再是波士顿当地的犯罪调查
It's not about Boston anymore. It's not a local investigation.
而是全国性事件 一定会影响股市
It's Wolf Blitzer. It's stock markets.
造成仇视伊斯兰教的激烈反应
It's politicians and knee-jerk reactions, anti-Muslim backlash...
若是评估错误
And what if we're wrong?
我意思是就没有退路了 这我经历过
I mean, there's no take-back. I've been through this before.
那是你的决定 但这绝对是恐怖行动
Look, your call, but we already know it is.
若是他们接着攻击芝加哥 纽约…
And a cell is activated, they hit Chicago or New York
或是华盛顿 那怎么办？
or Washington, what happens then?
我们怎么做 都会受到指责
The accusations are gonna come, no matter what we do.
这是恐怖袭击 我们会接手
It's terrorism. We'll take it.
你需要什么？
So, what do you need?
一个指挥中心 地方一定要够大
Command center. Really big one.
下午4:26
黑鹰港
这里就行了
This'll do.
把电脑分析与犯罪应对小组找来
I want CART team over there.
爆后调查小组在那个角落
Post-blast investigators in that corner.
我们得成立媒体中心
We need a media tent set up.
好了 我们得摆出物证
All right, let's get an evidence grid
所有物证陈列在墙边
started right over there against that wall.
手机通讯绝对会断讯
And I guarantee these are gonna crash,
所以要立刻架设地上通讯线
so let's get a bank of landlines up immediately.
没问题 1小时后就能启用
We're good, boss. We'll be up in an hour.
戴维斯局长 《纽约邮报》报导…
Commissioner Davis, the "New York Post" is reporting
一名20岁的沙国公民遭到起诉
a 20-year-old Saudi national has been charged.
- 你能确认吗？- 那是误报
- Can you confirm? - That is false.
目前没有人遭到起诉
We have not charged anyone at this time.
我们敬请民众协助调查工作
We are asking the public to help us supplement the investigation.
若有人持有马拉松的照片或影片
Anyone with photos or video of the marathon
请将它们交给波士顿警方
is encouraged to turn them in to Boston Police.
我需要访问以下数据库
I need you to give me access to the following databases...
旅行纪录…签证…
Travel, Visa...
有人得打电话给美国司法部
Someone needs to get on the phone with the United States Attorney's office.
申请移动通讯基站的搜查令
Get us some warrants for the cell phone towers right now.
包括ATT 威讯 T-Mobile
AT&T, Verizon, T-Mobile, all the way down the track.
让航空局知道 哪些飞机属于波士顿
Let T actical Aviation know, as of right now, Boston owns both those planes.
把它们开到洛根机场 我说的是T-5飞机
Get them both to Logan. No, I'm talking about the T-5's.
把它们从洛根转场到匡蒂科
They're gonna be cycling from Logan to Quantico. That's it.
调查局一分钟内 就收到一万两千封电邮
FBI servers just got 12, 000 e-mails in under a minute.
上帝啊
Holy Christ.
我们系统崩了 立刻恢复
And we're crashed. Get us back online now.
- 遵命 - 马上
- Yes, sir. Yes, sir. - Now.
下午4:38
波士顿医疗中心
28岁女子 杰西卡 肯斯基
28-year-old female, Jessica Kensky.
- 脉搏 101 - 血压84/45
- Pulse, 101. - BP's 84 over 45.
我们只能进行膝下截肢
Think the best that we could do is a BKA.
软组织坏死 没办法挽回了
The soft tissue's also compromised. I don't think this is salvageable.
软组织受损太严重了
There's way too much soft tissue damage.
一定要截肢 没别的办法
We gotta take it. There's nothing left here.
下午4:39
我需要生理盐水
I need some saline. We need to wipe off this flap.
贝丝以色列女执事医疗中心
无名20多岁男子
Male, late 20s with no ID.
他的腿情况不妙
The leg is not looking good.
血管没受损 但是无法供血
All right, the vessels are controlled, but there is no viability here.
我们必须进行截肢手术
Absolutely no blood supply. We'll have to amputate.
电锯
Saw.
左腿进行膝下截肢手术
Amputating below the knee, left leg.
终点线
我们在重建爆炸现场
We're recreating the scene.
第一爆炸位置
所有东西都原样放置
Put every item down exactly where it was found.
第二爆炸位置
把这些摊开来
We need this spread out here.
等等…先铺上一张纸
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Lay some paper down.
让它们风干 别破坏DNA
Let the stuff air dry. I don't want to degrade the DNA.
卡萝？接电话 听到吗？
Carol? Pick up the phone! Carol, can you hear me?
把纸铺在地上
Get this paper over here.
把烧毁和烧焦的衣物分开来
If you come across any clothing that's burnt or charred, separate that.
把手机交给电脑分析与犯罪应对小组
I need to have somebody collect these cell phones here, get 'em down to CART.
记住 伙计们
Okay, people, remember,
- 一定有人把炸弹带到现场 - 卡萝 给我回电话
- the bombs had to be carried in somehow. - Carol, you gotta call me back
听到留言马上回话
as soon as you get this message, all right?
也许是用大袋子或背包
on large bags and/or backpacks.
以充电器的品牌分门别类
Sort these out by adapter types.
带摄像头的手机都交给数据输入组
Anything with a camera, we need to get over to the import station.
GPS定位没问题吧？
Are those GPS tags coming through okay?
没问题
Yes, sir.
好 他就在这里
All right. Yeah, I got him right here.
甘迺迪总统图书馆不是爆炸现场
JFK Library's not an explosion.
卡萝 我一直在找你
Hello? Oh, Carol! I've been calling and calling!
汤米 你没事吧？
Tommy, Jesus. Are you okay?
我没事 你没受伤吧？
Yeah, yeah, I'm fine. You're not hurt, are ya?
没有 我妈在这里…
I'm fine, Tommy. My mother's here.
- 大家都在 - 谢天谢地
- Everybody's here. - Oh, thank God!
流言满天飞
The news is going crazy.
听说可能还有炸弹
They're saying there could be more bombs.
- 你一定要小心 - 放心 我得走了
- Please be careful, Tommy. - I will. I gotta go, all right?
我会尽快打给你
I'm gonna call you as soon as I can.
我爱你
I love you.
警长 下午我在对讲机里听到你 干得好
Hey, Sarge, heard you on the radio this afternoon. Hell of a job.
我也听到你的声音…
I thought I heard your squeaky-ass voice in my ear.
现在别烦我 麦克 拜托
Don't fuck around right now, Mike, please?
我没想烦你 你很棒
I'm not fucking around. You did good.
老婆 是我
Hey, honey, it's me.
亲爱的 我晚来了一天
Sweetheart, I've got out one day too late.
我会的
I will. No.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
那些家伙当时根本就不在现场
What are those guys doing here? They weren't even down there!
搞什么东东？
What the fuck is this, a joke?
他们是联邦探员 汤米 你得乖乖听话
They're the FBI and they're in charge, Tommy, so just do as you're told.
他们的上司一定会很惨
And their boss, I wouldn't wanna be that guy.
他得指挥现场
He's triple-fucked. One, he steps up and takes it.
- 还得破案 - 还有呢？
- Two, now he's gotta solve the thing. - What's three?
他还得整天揣摩嫌犯的心态
He's gotta walk around inside that life all day long.
- 打死我也不干这苦差事 - 闭嘴 汤米
- fucking shoot me four times and... - Button it up, Tommy.
这帮年轻人还都得仰仗你
These young guys are looking up to you.
今天你最好别给我拖后腿
I don't need the ass-ache from you today.
- 乖乖听话就好 - 好啦
- Just do as you're fucking told! - Fine.
没有自杀攻击的证据
We have no evidence this was a suicide attack.
这些土制炸弹应该是遥控引爆
So these IED's were most likely remotely detonated.
非常有可能是自制的
It is highly probable these bombs were homemade.
他们可能还有更多
It is likely that they made more.
州警觉得如何？
What does Mass State think?
我们需要国民警卫队的空中支援
I think we need to get air assets from the National Guard.
还需要更多战略小组
I think we need a couple additional tactical teams.
更重要的是 这儿只有两间厕所
But most importantly, there's two bathrooms
有一间还是坏的
in this place, and one's broken.
了解 我马上去处理
Right, I'll get on to that.
可以断定嫌犯不只一个人
It is safe to say that we're dealing with more than one individual,
他们有一定的能力
some degree of sophistication.
打扰下 德劳瑞探员
Excuse me, Agent Deh-law-ray?
- 特别探员德洛里耶 - 不好意思
- Special Agent DesLauriers. - Sorry about that.
- 我只想说… - 别乱说话
- Look, I just wanted to say... - It's not the time or place.
我只想说 我是重案组警长
I just want to say, I work Homicide.
我知道破案的关键是目击证人
I know one thing closes cases... witnesses.
所以应该派人到医院去问问伤者
So we oughta get our asses to the hospital, interview the victims.
也许有人看到什么
Could be someone saw something, no?
汤米 派一些警员过去
Tommy, get some of our guys on this.
记住 疑犯也可能是伤者
And keep in mind that the bomber could be among the wounded.
或许已和我们打过照面
We've seen it before.
所以一定要查明伤者身份
So let's get positive lD's on everybody coming into the hospital.
让这混蛋知道 他惹错了地方
Let's show this cocksucker he messed with the wrong fucking city.
我们之前关于警方逮捕沙特公民的消息 纯属误报
We're getting conflicting reports about the arrest of a Saudi national earlier.
戴维斯局长这次坚称
Now, Commissioner Davis at this time is insisting
尚未逮捕任何嫌犯
that no suspects have been arrested.
乔卡 我叫你买全脂牛奶 可这是半脂牛奶
Dzhokhar! I asked you to get whole milk. This is two percent.
她是小宝宝 又分不出来
It's milk. She's a baby. She can't taste the difference.
如果她生了病 我就分得出来
No, she can't, but I will when she gets sick.
到卧室喂奶 我都听不到新闻
Feed the baby in the bedroom. I can't hear the news.
这不是全脂牛奶 怎么喂？
What am I supposed to give her?
- 这不行的 - 去卧室喂奶吧
- This isn't gonna work. - Feed the baby in the bedroom.
- 我听不见了… - 我要全脂牛奶
- I can't hear... - I needed whole milk!
我会处理的 进卧室去 快去
I'll take care of it! Feed her in the bedroom right now! Go!
叫他去买全脂牛奶
Make him get whole milk.
我们不该把炸弹放在地上
We shouldn't have put the bombs ground level.
应该放在高一点的地方
We shoulda put that shit waist-high.
- 快去买牛奶 乔卡 - 什么？我不去
- Go get the right milk, Dzhokhar. Go! - What? No.
我不想听她唠叨 快去买牛奶
I don't wanna hear any more of her bullshit. Go get the right milk.
下午6:48
爆炸后4小时
我能问几个问题吗？
Mind if I ask you a couple of questions?
你有没有看到可疑的事情？
Did you see anything out of the ordinary?
- 任何可疑事件？- 没有
- Anything suspicious? - Nah.
你有没有看到有人放下袋子？
Did you see anybody put bags down or...
谢谢你 感激不尽
Thank you very much. Appreciate it.
有人问过你们话了吗？
Has anybody spoken to you guys yet?
还没？你叫什么 宝贝？
No? What's your name, sweetie?
我的膝盖痛死了 护士 你有扑热息痛吗？
My knee's killing me. You got some Tylenol back there?
我这儿啥都有 你要维柯丁吗？
We got all kinds of stuff, Sergeant. You want a Vicodin?
- 不要维柯丁 我要扑热息痛 - 扑热息痛
- No, no Vicodin. Tylenol. - Tylenol, Tylenol.
- 给我四片 - 没问题
- Make it four pills, please. - Okay, you got it.
谢谢你
Thank you.
查到他的名字了吗？
Hey, do we have a name on him yet?
没 救护员说他跟太太在一起
No, the EMT said he was with his wife at the site.
我只有这只戒指
But all I've got is this ring.
上面刻了"PB和J 8/25 12"
It's engraved "PB and J. 8-25-12."
- 她一定在另一家医院 - 我打电话问问
- She's gotta be in a different hospital. - Let me call around.
警方仍然封锁爆炸现场
They are still keeping people out of this area, obviously.
晚上8:38
东剑桥
15个街区 跟之前一样
Still that 15-block area that was mentioned earlier.
- 好了 - 谢谢
- Here you go. - Thank you.
- 炒饭和春卷？- 对 全在里面
- It's fried rice? Eggroll? - Yeah. Everything's in there.
太好了
Okay.
今天太可怕了
It's a very scary day today.
我叫丹尼 你叫什么？
My name is Danny. What was your name?
我叫卡拉
My name's Kara.
- 很高兴认识你 - 我也是
- Nice to meet you. - Nice to meet you, too.
- 你是波士顿人吗？- 对 我住这儿
- Are you from Boston? - Yeah, I live here.
我住在剑桥
Oh, I live in Cambridge.
- 那不远啊 - 是的 不远
- Oh, that's not far. - No.
周二 4月16日
爆炸后17小时
联邦调查局接管爆炸案调查行动
The FBI has taken over the criminal investigation into the bombings.
他们请民众提供任何有关的影像…
The Bureau is asking you for any visual...
- 嗨 约翰 - 嗨 怎么样？
- Hey, John. - Hey, what's up?
- 爆炸案真惨 - 惨透了
- This fucking bombing, huh? - Awful.
- 我们要支援吗？- 没有吧
- Are we gonna supplement this? - Not that I know of.
那是波士顿警局的案子
It's all BPD.
- 车子怎么了？- 全坏了
- What do you got? - Everything's busted.
收音机也坏了
The radio bracket's loose.
我打方向灯 车窗就会摇下来
The right window goes down when I put on the blinker.
方向灯怎么了？
Tell me this thing about the blinker?
我打右方向灯 右车窗就会摇下来
Yeah, it goes down, but only when I signal right.
最大的问题是
'Course, the big question this morning...
- 这是谁干的？- 真的很怪异
- Who did this? - That is fucking weird.
还有 他们作案动机是什么？
And why did they do this?
先生？抱歉打扰你
Excuse me. Sir? Sorry to disturb you.
- 这是杰西卡肯斯基吗？- 对 她是我女儿
- Is this Jessica Kensky? - Yes. She's my daughter.
我能理解
Hey, I understand.
- 我待会再回来 - 没关系
- I can come back, okay? - No, that's... Sorry.
我能帮什么忙？
How can we help you?
她能不能说话？
I just wanna know if she said anything at all?
- 有没有说什么？- 她没说什么
- If she communicated anything? - Not much.
她只问她先生在哪里
She just asked about her husband.
我们不知道 他叫派屈克道恩斯
We don't know where he is. His name is Patrick Downes.
- 你能帮忙找到他吗？- 交给我们吧
- Can you help us find him? - You leave that to us, okay?
- 好吗？- 谢谢
- Okay? - Thank you.
天呐
My God. Oh...
你们在这里干嘛？
What are you guys doing here?
这是怎么回事？
What the fuck happened out there? What's going on?
是不是盖达组织干的？
Is this fucking Al-Qaeda or what? Was it Al-Qaeda?
你们在我家吃圈圈饼干？
Are you fucking eating Cheerios on my couch?
- 汤米 - 到底是谁干的？
- Hey, Tommy... - Who did it? What are they saying?
是不是盖达组织？
What happened? Listen, was it Al-Qaeda or what?
给我们一点空间 好吗？
We're gonna give him some space, all right?
谁能告诉我们 到底是怎么回事？
Does someone wanna tell us what the hell happened?
叫大家都出去 给我出去
Get everybody outta here. Get the... get the fuck outta here now!
- 全都滚出去 - 我啥都没做
- Every fucking one of you! - Come on! What the hell did I do?
什么意思？快给我滚！
What do you mean? fucking come on!
- 对不起 - 给我滚出去！
- Sorry! - Get the fuck outta here!
你说了算 我们听你的
Whatever you want, Tommy. Whatever you need, whatever you need.
蓝色上衣
Blue coat.
我拿到了街区视频
I've got a street-block radius.
有点模糊
Yeah, it's a little grainy.
时间不对
Time doesn't match it.
你发现什么了？
You got 'em?
我不知道…我不知道…
I don't... I don't know.
没事了 宝贝
It's okay, baby.
我理解不了眼前的景象
I don't even understand what I saw.
我一直看到血 到处都是血
I keep seeing this blood. It's, like, everywhere.
我看到一只断脚…
I saw a foot next to...
孩子大概是从马拉松运动用品店来的
This boy from... Well, I think from Marathon Sport.
波士顿大学学生 好孩子
He looked like a little BU kid. Like a good kid, Carol, you know?
他是副店长
He had an assistant manager tag
他帮我抬那个女的
he helped, we moved her.
我们把她放下来
We... we laid her down.
血一直喷 他跪在她的血上面
Blood just started to spread, his knee was in her blood...
还有一个8岁小孩…
And then there was an eight-year-old boy.
就那么躺在地上
He was just laying there.
他的家人 父母只能被赶走 真是该死
They had to take his family away, and his parents, and fuck, he's fucking...
我满脑子都是这些景象
I got these images in my head.
永远都忘不了
They aingt going away.
你也在那里
And you were right there.
别怪我叫你去那里找我
Please don't be mad at me that I told you to come down there.
我不该叫你去那里
I shouldn't have told you to come down there.
你又不知道 那不是你的错
You never could have known. Baby, it's not your fault.
对不起 卡萝
I'm sorry, Carol.
我不该叫你去的
I'm sorry that I told you to come.
很抱歉 是我害你去那里的
I'm sorry that I put you there.
我们得逮到这些混帐东西
We gotta find these motherfuckers, Carol.
我们得逮到他们
We gotta get out there and find these motherfuckers
以免他们再害死别人
before they do this to somebody else.
往回倒三秒钟
Back it up three seconds.
老大
Boss!
这家伙 戴白帽子的
This guy. White hat.
再放一次
Play it again.
只有他别过头去
He's the only one that looks away.
联邦探员要跟你讲话 瑞克 这是桑德斯警长
Feds wanna talk to you. Rick. Sergeant Saunders.
谢谢你这么快就赶来
Thank you for coming so quickly.
不管什么 我啥都没干呢
Whatever it is, I didn't do it.
艾德说 你对这一区很熟？
Ed tells me you're familiar with this area?
对 怎么了？
Yeah, why?
- 放给他看 - 戴白帽子的
- Let's run it. - White Hat.
回放下
Play it back.
戴白帽子的那家伙？
The guy right there with the white hat?
- 就是他 对吧？- 我们认为是
- That's the guy, isn't it? - We believe so.
一定是他
It's gotta be.
假如我是戴白帽子的
Okay, so I am White Hat.
在2点45分
At exactly 2:45,
我在广场咖啡馆外 被监视拍到
I am seen by the surveillance videos outside the Forum restaurant, okay?
我们重建了 波尔斯顿街的爆炸现场
Now, Sergeant, as you can see, we've recreated the Boylston Street crime scene.
现在往左边走
Now, let's move left of boom.
哪里的左边？
Left of what?
爆炸点的左边
Left of boom. Left of the explosions.
我们得回溯他的行动 你对这条街很熟 对吧？
We need to trace him backwards. You know this street, right?
你也知道 哪里有监视摄像头
And you know which places have security cameras?
对 我知道你在做什么
Yeah, yeah. I know what you're doing.
那是终点线 你说2点45分？
That's the finish line there. You said 2:45?
没错
Correct.
他2点44分会在哪里？哪里能看到他
All right, so where is he at 2:44? Who can see him?
- 一定是在家居生活馆 - 找到家居生活馆
- It's gotta be Crate & Barrel. - Crate & Barrel, anybody?
正在查家居生活馆
Checking Crate & Barrel.
找到了
Yes, sir!
看到你了 下午2点44分
I see you. 2:44 p.m.
帽子上有高尔夫球商标和3号
The hat's got a golf logo along with the number three.
查出波士顿所有卖这种帽子的店
Okay. I wanna find every store in Boston that's selling that hat.
从信用卡收据查出姓名
Pull the names from the credit card receipts...
家居生活馆
Crate & Barrel.
进行脸部识别
then cross-check it against facial recognitions.
好 我2点44分在家居生活馆
Okay, Sergeant. I'm Crate & Barrel at 2:44.
有什么人会看到我？
Who sees me now?
对面的沃尔格林药品店
It's the Walgreen's that's across the street now.
- 艾伯路易牛排馆？- 艾伯路易牛排馆
- Abe 'n Louie's? - Abe 'n Louie?
正在查 艾伯路易牛排馆
Checking Abe 'n Louie's.
- 有谁在艾伯路易牛排馆找到什么？- 没有
- Anybody got Abe 'n Louie? - Nothing, sir.
- 没有？- 是的 没有
- No? - No, sir.
再想一想 还有哪里？
Come on, Sergeant. Where else?
等下 让我想想看
Gimme a minute, all right? Lemme think. Um...
街对面的中国餐馆？
Across the street, the Mandarin... The Mandarin?
不对 那里的摄影机角度不对
Nah, their cameras face the wrong direction.
那小子在酒馆偷了钱包
Remember, that kid stole a purse from Solas?
跑进皮特咖啡馆
He ran into Peet's.
我知道了 后湾俱乐部餐厅
Ah, I got it... Um, Back Bay Social Club!
泰迪去年在院子里新装了监控摄像头
Teddy put in new patio cameras last year.
后湾俱乐部餐厅
Back Bay Social Club.
搜寻后湾俱乐部餐厅
Searching Back Bay Social Club.
找到他了
I got him!
后湾俱乐部餐厅 下午2点40分
Back Bay Social Club. 2:40 p.m.
我拿到了他的脸的另一个角度 左眼 左下巴
I have a new angle on his face. His left eye, the chin.
还是不够清晰 做不了脸部识别
It's still not clear enough for facial recognitions.
传给电脑分析小组 看看能否补足特征
All right, push that out to CART team, see if they can fill in the blanks.
你干得不错 警官 继续
Doing great, Sergeant. Keep going.
下午2点42分 威士忌牛排馆
All right. 2:42 p.m. Whiskey's Steak House.
- 威士忌牛排馆 - 威士忌牛排馆
- Whiskey's Steak House! - Whiskey's Steak House!
找到了 2点37分 白帽子和别人站在一起
Got him. 2:37. White Hat's standing with someone.
他戴了一副飞行员太阳眼镜
It's a man wearing aviators.
他们相互认识
Looks like they know each other.
狗娘养的 你们这些混帐
Motherfucker! You fucking piece 'a shit!
有两名嫌犯
Two bombers.
- 亲我一下 - 不要
- Give me a kiss. - No!
- 那就出去 - 别这样
- Then get out. - Stop it.
给我出去
Get out.
你得把小兔兔绑在这里
There you go. You gotta put the bunny, like, right there.
不要
No.
- 要啦 什么？- 不要
- Yes. What? - No.
不要是什么意思？
What do you mean, no?
现场仍有大批警力
still a very heavy police presence.
据说联邦调查局已锁定嫌犯
The FBI reportedly zeroing in on a possible suspect.
他们侦查的速度比你想像的要快
They figured that out quicker than you thought, huh?
关于涉案的嫌犯各种疑问…
And amid all the questions about a possible suspect today...
来 我来帮你
Come on. I'll help you.
你的小宝贝不会绑鞋带
Your baby doesn't know how to tie her shoes.
我会帮她
I've got it.
- 乔卡？- 我不要吃
- Jahar? - Nah, I don't want any.
造成今天股市大幅动荡
caused chaos in the markets today.
联邦调查局
It also, we understand, forced the FBI
也取消了原定的记者会
to cancel what was a scheduled news conference.
至今仍未安排新的时间
It has never been rescheduled since.
我们的脸部识别系统怎么一无所获？
How can we have zero hits on facial recognition?
科技并不完善 影像也不完整
Well, the technology isn't perfect, Governor, we've got partial images.
角度也不合适
We've got bad angles.
这些照片很清楚啊
These are pretty clear fucking pictures.
有一名嫌犯戴着太阳眼镜
One of the suspects is wearing sunglasses.
- 试试国安局的系统 - 我们正在用
- Run it through the NSA's system. - We're using the NSA's system, sir.
我们得公布这些照片
We need to get these photos out to the public.
还不行 我们有一些线索 但…
Not yet. We have a couple of decent leads, but right now...
只要公布照片 市民就会揪出他们
We release these photos, the city eats these guys.
我同意
No, I agree.
那你为什么不去告诉他们？
So why don't you get over there and say something?
那是艾德的责任
Look, this is Ed's fucking deal right now, all right?
他们是别人的朋友 邻居 同事
These guys are somebody's friends, neighbors, co-workers.
- 你就是没种 - 我够有种的了
- You got no balls. - I've got fucking plenty of balls.
我只是不想和州长搅和在一起
I'm not getting involved with the Governor.
那我去说
I'll go over there and say something.
你还想被停职？
You wanna get yourself suspended again?
公布照片就表示
If we release those photos now, it tells the suspects
我们不知道嫌犯是谁
that we don't know who they are,
- 他们就占了优势 - 没错 但是…
- and that puts them ahead of us... - That's true, but...
但是什么？但是我们错了呢？
But what? But what if we're wrong?
他们若是无辜的呢？
What if these men are innocent?
他们若是穆斯林
And God forbid, they also happen to be Muslims,
我们会被骂死
we will be crucified!
我不觉得他们像典型的圣战士
They don't look like prototypical jihadists to me.
典型的圣战士长什么样？
What does a prototypical jihadist look like, Rick?
你有照片吗？
You got a photo of one?
你得遵守规矩
Okay, listen, that all sounds very by-the-book, Rick,
但我们得给市民一个交代
okay, but we owe people answers.
不能只坐在这里分析资料
We can't just sit back and keep analyzing data.
你的直觉是什么？
What does your gut tell you?
我的直觉是 就是他们干的
My gut tells me that these are probably our guys.
但我还没准备好 公布照片
But I'm not ready to release the photos.
你得再给我们多一点时间
Gotta give our people some more time to work.
那就这么决定吧
Okay. Okay, it's decided.
我们再多等一阵子
We'll wait.
到目前为止
At this time, there have been no new developments
波士顿马拉松爆炸案 没有任何进展
regarding the Boston Marathon bombings...
我们希望得到更多
We wish we had better information
有关嫌犯的消息
as far as them being able to find somebody right now.
但是目前仍在进行调查…
It just seems like it's an ongoing active search...
周四 4月18日
本来那是波士顿美好的一天
It was a beautiful day to be in Boston.
但是一瞬间…
And then, in an instant,
那一天的美好完全破碎
the day's beauty was shattered.
对全国人民来说 那是针对个人的
For millions of us, what happened on Monday is personal.
那是针对个人的
It's personal.
永远缅怀你们
我们一起祷告并哀悼
So we come together to pray and mourn.
但我们也团结一心
But we also come together today
重申这个城市的大无畏精神
to reaffirm that the spirit of this city is undaunted.
这个国家大无畏的精神永存
And the spirit of this country shall remain undimmed.
你们也表现出大无畏的精神
That's the spirit you've displayed in recent days.
- 嘿 小李 - 嘿
- Hey. Hey, Li. - Hey.
- 嗨 尚恩 - 嘿
- Hey, Sean. - Oh, hey...
我喜欢你的新眼镜
I like those glasses. Those are new, huh?
谢谢
Yeah, thanks.
我们课间休息 就替你也买了一杯
We needed a study break, so I thought you might like one, too.
谢了 小李
Thanks, Li, yeah.
椰奶香浓咖啡 很好喝
Coffee Coolattas. These are great.
我们该回去开工了
Uh, well, we should go back to work.
不过周六晚 柴克布朗乐团？
But, um, Saturday night, Zac Brown Band?
没错 我会的
Yeah, that's right. Are you guys...
你们全都能去吗？
I'll make sure all you guys are covered, so you're in.
只有我俩会去 可以吗？
It's just gonna be us. Is that cool?
- 好吗？- 那样更好
- Yeah? - That's better. Yeah.
- 真的吗？- 我更喜欢那样
- Yeah? - No, I prefer that, yeah.
- 太好了 再见 - 好吧
- Cool. Bye. - All right.
很高兴见到你们
Good seeing you guys.
安静下来 让我长话短说
All right, let's pipe it down so I can make this quick, please.
波士顿的案情不明朗
Situation in Boston remains in flux.
我们要随时准备提供协助
Let's be prepared to augment should they require our assistance.
康门街的限速…
Uh, speed limit on Common Street
约翰麦克凯伦警长 水镇警局
正式降至时速25英里
has now officially been down to 25 for a month.
教育劝导期已过
So, warning period is over.
教育劝导期一周前就到期了 长官
Quit giving warnings there a week ago, Sarge.
我已经给欧太太…
I gave Mimi O'Brien a citation
开了超速和驾照过期罚单
for speeding and expired registration.
那你比我胆子大
Well, you're a braver man than I am, Gunga Din.
下午3:30
爆炸后73小时
我们什么线索都没有
We got an information vacuum.
那不是我们要找的嫌犯
Those are not our guys.
而且你们的人
Meanwhile, you guys aren't any closer
也还没确认嫌犯的身份
to identifying the two we're really looking for.
我们必须公布那些照片
We need to release those pictures.
一旦公布了 情况就会失控
If we release the photos now, we have zero control.
我们太早摊牌 他们就会狗急跳墙
If we overplay our hand, we may force these guys to react.
各位 我能说话吗？
Gentlemen, if I may?
整个波士顿都在跟我们作对
Right now, Boston's working against us.
一般的命案没人会告发
As normal, you've got a murder, no one rats.
但是这次的情况完全不同
We don't got that problem, 'cause in this city,
只要是恐怖袭击 大家都会告发
when it comes to terrorism, everybody wants to talk.
现在大家告发的对象都是错的
Look, you got a lot of people talking, but they're talking about the wrong people.
只要公布照片 就会有人出面指证
You release the photos of our guys, sit back and listen. Trust me.
你们得让波士顿市民帮忙
You gotta start letting Boston work for us, I'm telling you.
我懂你的意思
I understand Boston,
但是我作不了主
but I can't just snap my fingers.
得要司法部长做出决定
This decision goes all the way up to the Attorney General.
把号码给我 我现在就打给他
Then give me his number. I'll call him right now!
这是我的城市 瑞克！
This is my fucking city, Rick!
给我公布那些照片！
Release the goddamn pictures!
再说一遍
Say again?
等一下 别挂断
Hold on, stay on the line.
别跟我说教 这是我的专业
Don't lecture me on intelligence, okay, Ed? That is what I do!
- 长官？- 干嘛？
- Sir? - What?
福克斯新闻台 拿到黑白帽子人的照片
White Hat, Black Hat. Fox got the pictures.
我们不提供消息 他们就要公布照片
They want what we have, or they're gonna release them.
再说一遍
Repeat that. Say that again.
福克斯新闻台20分钟后 就要公布照片
Fox is gonna release the pictures in 20 minutes, sir.
没得商量
With or without a consult.
我很支持跨部门的合作
Okay, I'm all about inter-agency cooperation,
但事情结束后 我一定要揪出…
but when this is over, I am gonna hunt down the piece of shit
泄漏照片的人渣 然后毁了他
that leaked those photos, and I will fucking ruin him!
我不会让福克斯新闻台 掌控调查行动
I'm not gonna let Fox News run this investigation.
总统专机一起飞 就公布照片
We will release the pictures as soon as the president is wheels up.
我们一开始锁定一名嫌犯
We initially developed one person of interest,
下午5:03
爆炸后74小时
并不知道他是否有同伙
not knowing if that individual was working alone or in concert with others.
调查局锁定第二名嫌犯
The FBI has developed a second suspect.
今天我们恳请民众协助…
Today, we are enlisting the public's help
指认这两名嫌犯
in identifying these two suspects...
调查人员表示 他们公布照片
Officials say they've made the images public now
是希望有人能够
because they need help in connecting the faces
出面指认嫌犯
of the potential suspects...
另一名跟在他的后面
the other walking just a short distance behind.
他们相信至少有人认得一名嫌犯
They believe that someone out there would recognize
也许两名嫌犯都会有人认识
at least one, perhaps both of these men,
并且能够向执法单位提供关键线索
and call in some vital information to law enforcement.
若是有任何线索 敬请连络联邦调查局
If you have any information at all, please reach out to the FBI.
马萨诸塞大学 达特茅斯分校
今晚正在调查一名年轻白人男子的身份
Investigators tonight are working to identify a young white man
他在第二次爆炸之后被拍到
He was in the crowd right before the second explosion.
他背着背包 拿着手机
He was carrying a backpack, talking on his cell phone,
身穿黑夹克 灰色帽T
wearing a black jacket, gray hoodie,
并且反戴一顶白色棒球帽
and a white baseball cap on backwards.
千万不要试图接近他
No one should attempt to apprehend him
除非你是执法人员
except law enforcement.
你看到新闻吗？
我必须再次强调
Let me reiterate that caution.
千万不要擅自行动
Do not take any action on your own.
指认这两名嫌犯
identifying these two suspects.
一定有人是他们的朋友
Somebody out there knows these individuals as friends.
我看到新闻 别再给我发短信
联邦执法单位相信
Federal law enforcement authorities now believe
至少有两人犯下爆炸案
that a team of at least two men carried out the bombings here.
嫌犯并不是单独行动
Not a lone wolf, but two men described tonight
你看到自己吗？"
这两名嫌犯持有武器 极度危险
as armed and extremely dangerous.
我们一开始锁定一名嫌犯
We initially developed one person...
They are now the world's most wanted men.
这两名头号通缉犯都是20来岁 第一名嫌犯
Two men in their 20s caught on tape. Suspect number one...
- 你在给谁发短信？- 没有啊
- Who are you texting? - No one.
把东西都装上车 该走了
Get everything packed in the car. It's time to leave.
好 可以把枪给我吗？
All right. Can I have my gun now, though?
我真的想要一把枪
I just like... I really want the gun now.
你会拿到枪的
Dzhokhar, you will get your gun!
- 几时？- 够了
- When? - Enough!
照片很模糊 不用担心
The pictures are blurry. They're no good.
才怪 照片很清楚
No, the pictures are good.
照片真的很清楚
Pictures are really good.
- 乔卡在哪里？- 不知道
- Hey, man, where's Jahar at? - I don't know.
你们看了记者会吗？
Did you guys see the press conference?
其中一个嫌犯长得跟他一模一样
One of the guys looks exactly fucking like him.
- 我也是这么说 - 胡扯 大家都太紧张了
- Yo, that's what I fucking said. - No way. Everybody's fucking paranoid.
- 他长得跟他一模一样 - 他发短信给我
- He looks exactly fucking like him. - He texted me.
他叫我帮他拿他的东西
He said to get some of his stuff.
你去拿 我得去看书
Go ahead, Dias. I got a study group to get to.
- 别偷拿我的东西 - 去你的
- Don't steal my shit! - Fuck you, man.
去你的 别碰我的东西
Fuck you! Don't touch my shit.
- 看个屁书啊 - 去死啦
- Study group, dickhead. - fucking asshole.
你不能把车子开上沙滩
Gnarly, man, you can't drive that thing on the beach.
你又会被警察抓
You're gonna get arrested again!
没事 我才不会被抓…
Relax, Bob. You can't get arrested...
这根抽完了
This joint is kicked.
没了 抽光了
It's all done. It's cashed out.
乔卡把大麻放在哪里？
Where does Dzhokhar keep his weed at?
大家最想要的衣橱
Of course. The coveted closet.
赞啦…赞啦…
Yep, yep, yep, yep.
靠 里面没有大麻
Shit. There's no weed in here.
那是什么东东？
What's that shit?
怎知？那是烟火吗？
Don't fucking know. Is that fucking fireworks?
他买烟火干嘛？
What the fuck does he need fireworks for?
- 这些是BB弹 - 你想说什么？
- Hey, these are fucking BB's, man. - What are you saying?
什么意思？
What are you fucking talking about, man?
这些是用来做炸弹的
This is fucking bomb shit.
你们难到看不出来吗？
Are you guys really that fucking high you can't see this shit?
- 怎么办？- 我不知道 是你找到的
- What the fuck do we do? - I don't know, man. You found it.
拜托 是我们找到的
Seriously? We found it.
小声啦 把东西放回去
Quiet the fuck down and put the stuff in the bag.
不能放在这里 放回去啦
We can't leave it here. Bag it up, man!
你以为我在干嘛？
What the fuck you think I'm doing, man?
我们仍在等待民众报案
We're still waiting to hear more about suspects.
照片公布后
With pictures being available to the public,
联邦调查局仍未接获…
the FBI has yet to receive any...
现在只有一个关键线索 这两名嫌犯的姓名
We now await one key lead, the names of these men.
晚9:14
爆炸后78小时
- 烫不烫？- 太烫了
- Is it hot? Yeah. - It's fucking hot.
- 你跳啦啦队折断指头？- 是的
- So you broke a finger cheerleading? - Yeah.
我做后空翻压到手指
I did a backflip and came down on my hand like that.
你是不是被队友抛得很高 然后…
Were you before, like, people throw you up really high, and then you come...
对 我高三那年摔到脑震荡
Yeah, I fell. I got a concussion my senior year.
我想站起来走路 左半身都麻痹
And I tried to get up and I tried to walk, and my entire left body was numb.
不能走路
Like, I couldn't walk.
我觉得好孤单
I feel like I'd be really lonely if I was here.
- 你也很孤单吧？- 还好啦
- Like, you're alone, right? - Yeah, it's okay.
一开始会 前三年最惨
In the beginning, like three years ago, it was harder.
现在我认识了新朋友
Now, it's like, you make new friends and you find new people.
你想要一把枪 现在你需要一把枪
You wanted a gun. Now you need a gun.
除非你知道谁有枪
Unless you know someone that has one.
242 你在哪里？
242, what's your status?
我在麻省理工学院的广场外面
I'm in the Quad, tucked next to the Koch building for the next 45.
盯着缅因街和凡赛街
Got my eyes on Main Street and Vasser.
然后休息30分钟 吃晚饭
After that, I got dinner break for 30.
让我来 好吗？
Can I do it?
你那里没动静
Denver 544. Koch is quiet.
过会儿去克雷斯吉礼堂
We're gonna rotate you over to Kresge.
是啊 这里很安静
Yeah, it is very dry out here.
你们说哪里 我就去
So if you want me to rotate, I'm absolutely ready.
收到
Copy that.
快抢他的枪
Grab the gun, Dzhokhar!
不…不…
No, no! No, no, no!
- 快点 - 他不肯放手
- Come on! - He won't fucking let go!
该死
Fuck you!
- 你干嘛不放手？- 让开！
- Why won't you let go? - Watch out!
不！
No!
- 走吧！- 现在怎么办？
- Let's go! - What now, motherfucker?
喂！
Hey!
放手 混帐东西！
Come on, you fucking piece of shit!
走吧！快点！
Let's go! Come on!
全体注意…
All units. All units.
这是全面通缉
This is a Commonwealth-wide all-points bulletin.
麻省理工学院校警 遭到枪击
We have a report of an officer shot at MIT.
尽快搜捕嫌犯
Requesting available units for search for suspects.
有两人逃离现场
Witnesses report two men fleeing the scene.
白人 中等身材
Caucasian, medium build, dark clothing.
持有枪械 多加小心
Suspects are armed. Use caution.
目前没有嫌犯的任何资料
A team, we have no suspect information at this time.
晚10:46
爆炸后80小时
一无所知
Nothing.
不好意思 你能帮个忙吗？
Sorry to bother, uh, can you help me real quick?
什么？
Sorry.
我只要你…
Yeah, I just want you to...
- 喂 干嘛？- 别动
- Hey, don't... - Do not move.
给我乖乖别动
Do not fucking move.
你叫什么？
What is your name?
曼…曼尼
Manny.
你知道马拉松爆炸案吗？
Yeah? Do you know about the Marathon bombing, Manny?
我知道
Yes, I know.
- 你知道是谁干的吗？- 不知道
- Do you know who did it? - No.
是我干的
I did that. You understand?
我刚才杀了一个警察
And I just killed a police officer.
你一定有很多钱 钱包给我
Bet you got a lot of money. Give me your wallet.
快点 把钱包给我
Let's go. Give me your wallet.
好…全都拿去
Yeah, yeah... Just take everything.
全都拿去
Just take it. Take everything.
你的名字不是曼尼
Your name is not Manny.
不是 我的名字是孟顿
No, it's... My name's Dun Meng.
只是听起来…听起来像曼尼
It a-sound... it a-sound like Manny. It sounds like Manny.
你敢再撒谎 我就毙了你
If you lie to me again, wallahi, I will kill you.
对不起
I'm sorry.
- 打开后车门 - 乖乖别动
- Open the back! - Do not fucking move.
打开后车门
Open the back!
- 打开后车门 - 好的 好的
- Open the back. - Okay, okay.
别乱来 快点 把车钥匙给我
Easy, buddy. Go ahead. Good. Give me the keys.
- 待在车上 - 好的
- Stay in the car. - Okay.
我去拿压力锅
I'll get the pressure cookers.
- 没了吗？- 没了 上车
- Is that it? - That's it. Get in the car.
该死
Shit.
没关系 冷静点
That's all right. Easy, easy.
你可以把车开走
You can just take the car.
没事 没事
It's all right. It's all right. It's all right.
跟着我 走吧
Follow me. All right. Let's go.
什么都别说
Do not say anything. Stay quiet.
看着我…
Look at me. Look at me. Look at me.
你可以回到车上 懂吗
Get in the car. You understand?
- 你要回到车上 - 好的
- You're gonna get in the car... - Yes, yes.
- 给我安静点 - 好 好
- and you're gonna be quiet. - Yes.
好吗？走吧
All right? Let's go.
快上车
Get in the car.
快给我上车
Get in the car right now.
- 乔卡？- 干嘛？
- Jahar? - Yeah?
- 看着他 - 好
- Watch him. - All right.
- 这辆车有iPod插座吗？- 啊？
- Yo, does this have an iPod plug-in? - Huh?
- 这辆车有iPod插座吗？- 没有
- Does your car have an iPod plug-in? - No. No.
你确定？那有没有蓝牙
You're sure? What about Bluetooth? You got Bluetooth?
我想用我的手机放音乐
I can plug my phone in and play some stuff?
抱歉 没有蓝牙
Sorry, there's no Bluetooth.
这里有没有人管你死活？
Do you have anyone that cares about you?
这里没有人管我死活
Nobody care about me here.
那就戴上安全带
Then put on the seatbelt.
不准任何人进来
No one gets through, you hear me?
快给我氧气
We need oxygen now.
我不知道 他的状况很糟
I don't know, Travis, it's bad.
对 是尚恩
Yeah, it's Sean. I...
他们想抢走他的枪 但是他不放手
They tried to take his gun, but he wouldn't give it up.
他们向他开枪
They shot him. They...
没有脉搏 他死了
No pulse. He's gone.
进入水镇
哥 开慢点 别超速
Dookie, take it easy. Stay under the limit.
靠 这辆车跑得真快
Damn. This thing moves.
真的？我能开吗？
Really? Yo, can I drive it?
- 你想开？- 对
- You wanna drive it? - Yeah.
- 做梦 - 为什么？
- No way. - Why?
我没开过奔驰 我真的想开奔驰
Bro, I've never driven a Benz. I really wanna drive a Benz.
你不能开这辆车
Jahar, you're not going to drive this car.
别做梦了
Get over it.
你开错方向了 警察叔叔
You're going the wrong way, Officer.
转过来！
Hey! Turn around! Hey, you!
你们要去哪儿？回家？
Where are you heading? Home?
- 我们要去他妈妈家 - 别待在街上
- We're going to his mother's house. - All right, get off the street.
波士顿马拉松爆炸案被形容为…
The Boston Marathon tragedy is being described
911事件后最严重的国内恐怖袭击
as the worst act of domestic terrorism since the September 11 th attacks.
但是有别于世贸中心的袭击
However, unlike the attacks on the World Trade Center...
去他们的
Fuck them!
你知道这全是屁话吧？
You know that's bullshit, right, Manny?
- 知道 - 911事件…
- Yes. - 9/11...
双子塔不是穆斯林干掉的
Muslims didn't blow up those buildings.
- 是美国政府干的 - 我知道
- The U.S. government did. - Yes, I know.
- 你知道？- 我知道
- You know? - I know.
你是真的这么认为
Are you saying yes because you believe it,
还是不想被我们杀死？
or are you saying yes because you don't want us to kill you?
我不知道911事件是谁干的
Sorry, I don't know who did it. 9/11...
你得自我教育 兄弟
Yo, you need to educate yourself, dog.
这就是这个国家的问题
For real, that's the problem with this country.
没人知道真相 美国充满了假象
No one knows what goes down. America is fake as fuck.
这一切都是美国政府干的
The government did all that shit. The government.
好让美国人痛恨穆斯林
To make Americans hate real Muslims.
自称在911现场的人都是演员
A lot of people who say they were at 9/11, they're all actors.
- 我不知道 - 你现在知道了
- I didn't know that. - Well, now you know.
你被媒体洗脑了 当然不知道
Of course you didn't. You're conditioned by the media.
对
Yeah.
把你的提款卡拿给乔卡
Take your ATM card. Give it to Jahar.
你的密码是什么？
What is your PIN number?
我要你的密码 是什么？
Your PIN number! I need your PIN number.
- 密码是什么 - 6228
- What is your PIN number? - 6-2-2-8.
- 听到吗？- 什么？
- Did you get that? - What?
- 6… - 6228
- 6... - 6-2-2-8.
6228 知道了
6-2-2-8. Okay.
尽量多取点款
Okay, Jahar, get as much money as you can, okay?
- 我看起来糟透了 - 乔卡！
- Well, I look wack as fuck. - Jahar!
- 尽量多取点钱 - 好啦
- Get as much money as you can. - All right.
时代广场在…
Times Square is...
42街和百老汇街口
42nd Street and Broadway...
砰！
Boom!
抵达纽约时间…3小时42分
Time to New York, 3 hours, 42 minutes.
拜托 放我走 你们可以把车开走
Please, can I just leave and you can take the car?
- 你想走？- 你可以…
- You want to leave? - You can just...
你想下车？你要我下车？
You want to leave the car? Are you asking me to leave the car?
- 去你的 - 不是…不是…
- Fuck that. - No, no, no.
我下车 你把车子开走
I leave the car, you take the car.
你哪儿都别想去 你要留在车上
No, you're not going anywhere. You're gonna stay right there.
我不会报警
I won't... I won't call the police.
拜托 我在中国有家人
Please, I have a family in China.
我有妈妈 我有爸爸
I have a mama, I have a daddy.
我有弟弟
I have a brother.
我有…
I have...
拜托 我不会告诉给任何人
Please? I don't call anyone.
放我走
Just let me go.
给我闭嘴
Shut the fuck up.
把油箱加满
Fill up the tank.
只限现金
加油机坏了 只能用现金
The pump's busted. It's cash only.
- 顺便买点吃的 - 好 你要吃什么？
- Get something to eat, too. - All right. Want something to eat?
不要
No.
- 你不饿？- 我不饿
- You're not hungry? - No, that's okay.
我会给他带点吃的
I'll get him something.
我们会开很久
Gonna be a long ride.
- 去你的！- 该死
- Fuck you! - Fuck!
发生什么事？
What the fuck happened?
快报警！快报警！
Call the police! Call police, please!
- 怎么回事？- 快报警！
- What happened? - Please call!
他们挟持我
Two people, they kidnapped me.
他们自称是马拉松炸弹客
They said they're the Marathon bombers...
快报警！
Call the police!
911应急中心 您有什么紧急状况？
9-1-1 recorded line. What's the nature of your emergency?
这是一家美孚加油站
I am in Mobil gas station.
有个人跑进来说 有人想向他开枪
I have one claiming someone wants to shoot him.
他在店里 他想要离开
And he stay inside, and he won't leave.
我能跟他说话吗？
Can I speak with him?
喂？请帮帮我！
Hello? Please help me! Please help me!
两个人劫持我的车 他们有枪
Two people, they came to my car, and they have guns.
发生劫车案
All units, possible carjacking.
两名20来岁白人男子
At least two males, white, mid-twenties
纪念街和大河街口的美孚加油站
at the Mobil station off Memorial and River Street.
目击者是亚裔男子 姓名不明
Witness is an Asian male, name unclear.
接线员听不太懂他的话
Emergency operator had trouble understanding him.
要求警车前往调查
Requesting units to investigate.
488号警车回应
Patrol Unit 488 responding.
我不懂 我们干嘛换车？
I don't understand. Why are we doing this?
干嘛要换车？
Why are we doing this?
为啥非得换车 这辆车这么豪华
Why do I have to take this car? This car's so much better!
因为他们在找这辆车
Because they're gonna be looking for us now in this one.
为什么不换别的车？
No, but then why don't we just get another car?
好一点的车
We'll just get, like, a better car.
- 不如偷一辆兰博基尼 - 快去拿炸弹
- We can jack a Lambo... - Get the fucking bombs.
- 或者别的好车 - 快去拿炸弹 好吗
- or something actually working. - Get the fucking bombs, all right?
听我说
Just listen to me for a second!
如果再偷一辆车 真正的好车
If we get another car, like, an actual car...
拜托 塔米尔南 听我说
Listen to me, Tamerlan, please! Listen to me!
别把我当小孩 听我说
Stop treating me like a fucking baby! Listen to me!
都是你害我分心
You fucking distracted me! You distracted me.
所以他才会逃走 了吗？
That's why he got away. Do you understand that?
又不是我的错 开什么玩笑？
What? This is not my fault! Are you fucking kidding me?
你坐在他旁边 我一直坐在后面
This is your fault! You were up front with him!
我去买吃的 你这王八蛋…
I was in the back the whole time, and I went to get snacks, you piece of shit.
别怪我！你别怪我！
Don't fucking accuse me! Don't fucking accuse me!
- 给我闭嘴 了吗？- 好啦
Fucking be quiet right now. Do you understand?
- 乔卡… - 好啦
- Dzhokhar... - Okay. Okay.
- 给我乖乖闭嘴 - 好的
- You be fucking quiet right now. - All right, all right.
- 不然我就亲手毙了你 - 好吧
- Or I'll fucking kill you myself! - All right, all right.
- 懂了吗？- 懂了
- Do you understand me, Jahar? - Yeah. Yeah.
我会亲手毙了你
I'll fucking shoot you myself!
- 好的 - 明白吗？
- All right. Yeah. - Do you understand me?
你害我分心 他才会逃走
You distracted me. That's how he got away.
照我说的做 把炸弹放在后车厢
You're gonna do as I say and grab the fucking bombs and put them in the trunk.
- 好的 - 乖乖听话 明白？
- All right. - And do as I fucking say, you understand?
- 好啦 - 动作快点
- Yeah. - Right now.
快给我上车！
You fucking get in the car!
我会找地方弃车
I'll find somewhere to ditch the Mercedes.
你要跟着我
And you will follow me.
- 听到了吗？- 知道了
- Got it? - Yeah.
- 菲尔 怎么样？- 他在那里 警长
- Hey, Phil, what's up? - He's over here, Sarge.
- 怎么回事？- 我什么都问不出来
- Hey. What's going on? - I can't get a word out of him.
让我来问 你好吗？没事吧？
Let me talk to him for a second. Sir, how are you? You okay?
有两个人抢走我的车
Two people, they take my car.
在那里…
They take my car over there in the...
他们开车乱逛了一小时 他们说他们放了…
They drive me around for, like, an hour, and they say they put a...
- 等等 你说什么？- 他们说
- Wait, what did you say? - These people, they tell me
他们要到纽约放炸弹
they gonna do the explosion in New York.
什么？
What?
他们是马拉松炸弹客
They're the Marathon race bombers.
冷静点 冷静一下
Wait, no, no, calm down. Just calm down for a second.
你刚才说到 马拉松炸弹客？
Did you just say "Marathon bombers"?
你说他们自称是马拉松炸弹客？
They said to you that they were the Marathon bombers?
对 他们告诉我 他们是马拉松炸弹客
Yes, they told me. They are the Marathon bombers!
听好 你开什么车？
Listen to me. What kind of car do you drive?
黑色奔驰SUV
It's my black Mercedes SUV.
车上有卫星定位系统
That car has a GPS.
追踪序号是…3422347
The tracking number is 3422347.
- 你怎么会知道？- 我背下来的
- Well, how do you know that number? - I just remember.
他们很危险 你得抓住他们
Please, they're very dangerous. You have to catch them.
你能逃出虎口 真的很有种
You know what? It took a lot of balls to escape like you did.
你很勇敢 知道吗？
Hey, you're a very brave guy. Do you hear me?
快去抓住那些混帐东西
Go catch those motherfuckers!
靠 这又不是我的错
Fuck! Fuck! Wasn't my fucking fault!
不是我的错
Wasn't my fucking fault!
该死 该死
Look, you fucking fuck!
留意一辆黑色奔驰SUV
All units, be on alert for a black Mercedes SUV,
有可能是劫车嫌犯
possible carjacking suspect.
卫星定位显示 车子在水镇
GPS shows the vehicle in Watertown, south of Mount Auburn Street.
B364号警车回应
Baker 364 responding.
克里斯 今晚看来没得睡了
All right, Chris, maybe stay awake tonight, you know?
该换换节奏了
Just for a change of pace.
凌晨12:43
水镇
警长 这是乔伊
Sarge, it's Joey.
我好像看到了那辆奔驰车
Think I got eyes on that Mercedes called in earlier.
我要掉头跟上去
I'm gonna flip around and follow him.
他停在洛雷尔街和戴克斯街口
He stopped. He's on Laurel off Dexter.
等一下 我就在你后面
Hold up, Reynolds. I'm coming in behind you.
准备好就闪灯
Light 'em up whenever you're ready.
靠…靠…
Fuck! Fuck! Fuck! Fuck! Fuck!
哇靠！我的老天！
fucking shit! Jesus fucking Christ!
对方开枪！对方开枪！我需要支援！
Shots fired! Shots fired! I need units down here!
莫瑞街61号！
61 Laurel Street!
- 老天 乔伊 你没事吧？- 我没事
- Jesus Christ! Joey, you all right, man? - Yeah, I'm all right!
放下武器出来…
Drop your weapon and come out...
天啊！
Jesus!
投降吧！你无处可逃了！
Give it up! You got nowhere to go! Fuck!
全体注意 警员和嫌犯在剑桥爆发枪战
All units, we have shots fired at the vehicle in question from Cambridge.
发生在戴克斯街
Last seen near Dexter Ave.
水镇需要支援
We need units to assist in Watertown.
- 我能用枪吗？- 不 快拿炸弹
- Can I use the gun? - No, no, grab the bomb.
- 让我用枪 - 快去拿炸弹
- Let me use it. - Grab the bomb. Get it.
用那辆车当掩护
Joey, use the car for cover!
快点火…快点火…
Light it! Light! Light, light, light!
天哪
Ahh! God!
天啊 该死
Oh, Jesus! God fucking damn it!
- 该死 乔伊！- 警长 你在哪里？
- Fuck! Joey! - fucking, Sarge, where are ya?
跟着我！听我的声音！
Follow me! Follow my voice!
天啊！我这里需要支援
Jesus! Dispatch, I need backup down here!
他们有炸弹 对方开枪
They've got explosives. Shots fired! Shots fired!
该死！卡弹 拜托！
Shit! Jammed. fucking come on!
他们是什么人？
Who the fuck are these guys?
水镇警方通报
Watertown P.D. reporting shots fired
黑色奔驰车上 有人开枪
from black Mercedes matching APB.
D984警车回应
Delta 984 responding.
该死
Oh, shit! Fuck!
- 怎么回事？- 快到地下室！
- Sarge, what's going on? Sarge! - Get the fuck in the basement!
我们可以搞定他们
We can take 'em. We can take 'em.
你还有几颗子弹？
How many clips you got?
- 这是最后一颗 - 可恶
- This is my last one. - Shit!
去死吧！
Fuck you!
干得好 好样的
Doing good. You're doing very good.
你没事吧？
You okay?
我要去拿我的机关枪 别动
Fuck! I'm going for my machine gun! Stay here.
你们这些混帐王八蛋
You cocksucking piece of fucking shit!
搞什么？我拿到小铁鎚！
What the fuck?! Sarge, I got a mini-sledge!
给他们好看！
Give 'em hell, brother!
喂 是我 乔伊
Whoa! Miguel! Miguel, it's me, Joey!
你没事吧？
Holy shit, dude! Are you all right?
我没事 向前推进 掩护我
I'm all right. Push onto Laurel.
掩护我
And cover my ass. I'll get behind you.
- 上吧 - 慢慢来
- Let's go! - Go slow.
快上
Okay, go, go!
点不着
It won't light.
- 快啊 - 快呀 可恶
- Come on, come on... - Come on, you fucking...
- 快点 - 该死！
- Come on, come on! - Fuck!
我靠！
Jesus! Fuck!
该死
Fuck!
欢迎来到水镇 混帐东西！
Welcome to Watertown, motherfucker!
去你的 臭婊子！
Fuck you, bitch!
米格 你没事吧？
Christ! Miguel, you all right?
去死吧！
Fuck you!
惨了
Shit!
乔伊！
Joey!
乔伊 快拿枪
Joey, get the gun! Get the gun!
该死 乔伊！
Fuck! Joey!
该死
Fuck!
撤退！撤退！
Fall back! Fall back! Go, go, go!
快躲到车子后面
Come on! Let's get to the car!
快到我后面
Go! Get behind me! Get behind me!
快 快
Come on, come on!
他们有炸弹 还向我们猛开枪
They got fucking bombs, Sarge! They're shooting at us!
还用你说 我从后面包抄他们
Yeah, no shit. I'm gonna flank 'em.
乔伊！
Joey!
我们的支援来了
We got units coming in!
就是这一刻了 乔卡
This is it, Jahar. This is it.
- 我的腿 - 你没事吧？
- My fucking leg! - You okay? Are you okay?
你一定要准备好
You should prepare. Now.
还想要吗？
Want some more, motherfuckers? You want some more?
- 搞什么？- 天哪
- The fuck? - Jesus!
老唐 掩护我后方
Donohue! On my six!
开车到纽约 完成任务
Take the car to New York. You finish it!
我们要杀光他们
We're killing them all. We're killing them all!
把他们全炸死
Go fuck 'em up.
发生大爆炸… 发生大爆炸…
Loud explosions! Loud explosions! Loud explosions!
该死
Fuck.
弟 快走！
Dookie, go!
毙了他！
Take him out!
警员受伤！快叫救护车！
Officer down! We need an ambulance!
马上叫救护车！
Get an ambulance now!
把手压住那里
Put your hands on there! Put your hands on there!
撑着点
Hold on, Donohue.
把他带走 撑着点
Get him out of here! Hang in there! Hang in there!
快叫救护车 我们需要协助
Get an ambulance! We need help! Officer down!
快上 快上
Go, go, go!
我正在追捕一辆黑色奔驰SUV
This is Delta 984 in pursuit of a black Mercedes SUV
沿洛雷尔街向东
heading east on Laurel Street!
停车！停车！
Stop the vehicle! Stop the vehicle!
搞什么？
What the...
该死
Fuck!
- 给我趴在地上！- 怎么回事
- Get the fuck on the ground! - What the fuck's the matter with you?
猪头
BPD, you fucking morons!
我们只听到黑色车 对不起！没事吧
We heard black truck! I'm fucking sorry! You all right?
- 他在那里 快点 - 快追 快追！
- That's him right there! Come on! - All right, let's go! Move out!
77-16呼叫总部
77-16 to Control.
请派一辆救护车到洛雷尔街
Need an ambulance on Laurel Avenue.
嫌犯被捕 他中了枪又被车辗过
Suspect in custody. Shot and run over.
重覆 他中了枪又被车辗过
Repeat. Shot and run over.
我得戒烟了
I gotta fucking quit smoking.
他不见了
He's gone.
- 电击器 - 充电到200
- Paddles. - Charge to 200, please.
- 没有脉搏 - 充电到200
- Nothing. No pulse. - Charging to 200.
- 让开 - 让开
- All clear. - Clear.
- 有没有反应？- 没有
- Anything in response? - No.
充电到200
Raise the charge to 200.
- 充电中 - 让开
- Charging. - Clear?
- 让开 - 使用胸内电击片
- Clear. - Internal paddles.
直接电击心脏
Let's have a direct shock to the heart.
请同时按压胸部
Chest compression, please, while we do this.
你们得退后 我要扫描他的指纹
I need you to step back right now. This has to happen now.
- 出去 - 让我一下
- Get outta here! - Excuse me, step back.
我是联邦探员 我要扫描他的指纹 退后
I'm with the FBI. This has to happen right now. Just stand back.
天啊
Good Lord.
给我海绵 我得帮他止血
Give me some more sponges. I gotta stop the bleeding in here.
- 准备电击器 - 没有脉搏
- Get the paddles ready. - Nothing. No pulse.
- 让开 - 好了
- All clear. - Clear!
- 有反应吗？- 没有
- Anything? - Nothing.
我要宣布死亡时间
Okay, I'm calling it.
凌晨1 35 记录
1:35 a.m. Mark it.
凌晨1:35
塔米尔 南沙尼耶夫
Tamerlan Tsarnaev.
爆炸后82小时
和妻子凯瑟琳住在剑桥
Lived in Cambridge with his wife
还有弟弟乔卡
Katherine and his younger brother Dzhokhar.
派特别行动小组 和炸弹专家去清理现场
Get HRT, S.O.G., bomb techs over there right now and shut it down.
建立封锁区
Give me a hard perimeter. Evacuate a block.
- 撤离两个街区的居民 - 遵命
- Make it two blocks. - Got it.
- 有个问题 - 怎么了？
- We have a problem. - What's up?
- 黑帽人 塔米尔南沙尼耶夫 - 怎么
- Black Hat, Tamerlan Tsarnaev? - Yes.
- 我们可能知道他 - 知道什么
- We might have known this guy. - Known him how?
他出现在恐怖分子观察名单
He popped up on a Guardian watch list.
把名单拿给我
All right, get me the list.
就在这里
Right fucking here!
在追捕过程 一名嫌犯身受重伤
During the pursuit, one of the suspects
送到医院后
was critically injured, transported to hospital,
已被宣布死亡
where he was pronounced dead.
警方正在水镇
Now, here's where we stand.
展开大规模搜捕行动
Extensive manhunt in Watertown...
一名曾和嫌犯接触的 亚裔男子告诉警方
Report that an Asian male who came in contact with the suspects
这对兄弟的下一个目标是纽约市
told police that the brothers discussed New York City as their next destination.
晨4:48
水镇指挥中心
听说了吗？查出黑帽人的身份了
You heard? We got positive ID on Black Hat.
我们听说 沙尼耶夫是黑帽人
Yes, Tsarnaev. We heard. Black Hat.
那白帽人呢？
What about White Hat?
汤玛斯曼尼诺
我们能确定他还在封锁区内吗？
How sure are we that he's still within the perimeter?
波士顿市长
天色太暗 很难确定
It's hard to be sure in the dark like this.
警员们都累坏了
My guys are running on fumes.
- 两间棚屋 - 根据线索
- Two sheds. - We're tracking reports.
白帽人坐上一辆计程车
A taxi picked up a guy matching White Hat's description
从水镇到南站
from Watertown to South Station.
他可能想去纽约
Could be he's on his way to New York.
好吧
Okay.
警告纽约州长古莫和市长彭博
Warn Governor Cuomo and Mayor Bloomberg.
至于波士顿
As for Boston, I'm calling it.
我决定了 封锁整座城市
We're shutting down the city until further notice.
所有公共运输系统都要停运
Inform all transit systems and let's get a PBA out immediately.
并且建议居民留在家中
All civilians are asked to please shelter in place.
我们要搜遍全城每一寸土地
Every inch of this city is getting searched.
你确定要这么做 州长？
You positive you wanna do this, Governor?
这等于是实施戒严令
That's close to martial law.
请警员不要随意踹开家门
T ell your people to be judicious with the door kicking.
法律仍然保障人民权利
We got laws. People still have rights.
这个杀人犯不能再造成任何损伤
This murderer is not causing any more harm to this city.
我们要封锁波士顿市
We're shutting it down.
周五 4月19日
爆炸后89小时
州政府发出重要通知
State Control with an important announcement.
由于对一个嫌犯的追捕行动
Due to the ongoing manhunt for a person wanted...
警方正在全力追捕
Police in your area are conducting an ongoing manhunt
马拉松爆炸案的嫌犯
for a person wanted in connection with Monday's Marathon bombing.
以下城镇所有的商家都必须关闭
All businesses in these towns remain closed until further notice.
水镇 牛顿市
Residents in Watertown, Newton,
沃尔瑟姆 贝尔蒙特 剑桥的居民
Waltham, Belmont, Cambridge are advised...
都建议留在家中
are advised to stay indoors.
居民们不要随意开门
Residents should remain and not answer the door
除非对方是警员
unless it is a police officer.
并建议居民远离窗户
Residents are advised to stay away from windows.
把门窗关紧 回到屋里
Close your windows. Go back inside your houses.
千万不要开门
Don't answer the door.
波士顿警察 请开门
Boston Police, open the door, please.
你家里有别人吗？
You got anybody in the house with you?
没有 一切都没事
No, it's okay. It's cool.
你应该待在屋里
You're supposed to be staying inside.
出去透透气就回家
So get a little air and then head back, all right?
- 我会的 - 那就好
- Will do. - All right, pal.
- 谢了 - 谢谢你
- Thanks. - Thank you.
我们走吧
All right, let's move.
联邦调查局下令
Per FBI command, anyone making contact
任何人和嫌犯的妻子凯瑟琳罗素接触
with suspect's wife Katherine Russell
都必须留在原处 等待指令
is instructed to detain in place and advise.
不能宣读权利 不能讯问
Do not Mirandize. Do not interview.
- 他说不能宣读权利 - 我听到了
- He just said no Miranda. - Yeah, I know.
- 我从没听过这种事 - 我也没有
- I mean, I never hear of that. You? - No. Never.
- 这是谁下的令？- 不知道 司法部长 中情局？
- Who would call that? - I don't know. AG? CIA?
还是总统？我怎么会知道
fucking President. How do I know?
他有很多DVD 拳击 摔角
Basically he's got home videos, boxing, wrestling.
我们都会看的影片
Stuff we see all the time.
还有一大堆A片
And porn. A lot of fucking porn.
这家伙看的A片 比本拉登还要多
This guy watched more porn than Bin Laden.
华盛顿当局 要派一个小组讯问他太太
Okay, Washington is flying up a team to interview the wife.
马上把她带到局里
Let's get her picked up immediately.
查到白帽人的手机位置
Sir, we just got a hit on White Hat's phone.
- 哪里？- 马州大学达特茅斯分校
- Whereabouts? - U Mass Dartmouth.
- 派人质拯救队过去 - 他们正赶去
- Let's get HRT to U Mass Dartmouth. - They're on their way, sir.
猪头
Dickhead.
你逃课会被臭骂一顿
You're missing class for an ass-whupping.
- 睁大眼睛 伙计 - 我只是提醒你
- Wide open, man. - I'm just letting you know.
我不想去那场愚蠢的聚会
I don't wanna go to Crystal's stupid party.
- 上…上… - 该死！
- Go, go, go! - Shit!
趴下！趴下！
Get down! Get down! Get down!
让我看到你们的脸！
Let me see your face! Let me see your face!
别动 看着我
Don't move! Don't move! Look at me.
报告 没有找到白帽人
Victor 1-1 to Talk. We do not have White Hat.
屋里安全 拆弹小组和取证小组可以过来
Room is clear for EOD and Forensics.
重复 没有找到白帽人
Repeat, we do not have White Hat.
没有 没找到 对
No. Negative. Right.
线报说 学生向白帽人买大麻
We're getting tips from kids saying they buy their pot from White Hat.
他是马州大学最大的毒贩
Apparently, he's the biggest dealer at U Mass.
局长 黑鹰港打来电话
Commish, they just called from Black Falcon.
嫌犯妻子已被抓获
They got the wife.
上午11:26
爆炸后93小时
和你想像的不一样 对吧？
Not what you were expecting, huh, Commish?
每次都不一样
It never is.
特别探员 德洛里耶斯？
S.A.C. DesLauriers?
- 我找特别探员 德洛里耶斯 - 我是瑞克德洛里耶
- I'm looking for S.A.C. DesLauriers. - Rick DesLauriers.
我是麦克汤玛斯 能谈谈吗？
Hi, I'm Mike Thomas. May I have a word with you?
我们要接手讯问
We're gonna handle the interview from here.
- 你们跟她谈过了吗？- 还没有
- Have any of you spoken to her yet? - Not yet.
- 这是她所有的资料 - 我们都有了
- This is everything we have on her. - We're good. We're good.
谢谢 现在由我们接手
Thank you, gentlemen. We will take it from here.
你敢对先知不敬？
You disrespect the Prophet?
凯瑟琳 还有更多炸弹吗？
Katherine, are there more bombs?
我是薇洛妮卡
My name is Veronica.
我出生在难民营
I was born in a tent with three walls
四处都有联合国儿童基金会的标志
that said UNICEF on the sides
我母亲连自己的名字都不会写
to a mother who could not write her own name.
你出生在满是鲜花和气球的病房
You were born in a room full of flowers and balloons.
你母亲是护士 她都叫你凯蒂
Your mother is a nurse. She calls you Katie.
- 你对我一无所知 - 你的闺蜜吉娜克劳佛
- You know nothing about me. - Your best friend, Gina Crawford,
在剑桥的一家星巴克工作
works at a Starbucks in Cambridge
你一边喝焦糖玛奇朵
where you tried to convert her to Islam
- 一边劝她改信伊斯兰教 - 你知道什么
- between skinny caramel macchiatos. - You know nothing.
还有更多炸弹吗？
Are there more bombs?
更多炸弹客？
More bombers?
爆炸一发生你就发短信给吉娜
You sent Gina a text right after the bombing
你说 叙利亚和其它地方…
that said, "A lot more people are killed
每天都有更多人死亡？
every day in Syria and other places.
无辜平民
Innocent people."
你看到电视画面吗？
Did you see the footage on television?
我们在你的公寓 找到炸弹残留物
We found explosive residue from the bombs in your apartment.
厨房流理台和洗碗槽都有
On your kitchen table. In your kitchen sink.
你替女儿做早餐的厨房
The kitchen where you made breakfast for your daughter.
还有更多炸弹吗？
Are there more bombs?
你大二那年 在酒吧认识塔米尔南
You met Tamerlan in a bar your sophomore year
- 在萨福克大学 - 我要律师
- at Suffolk University. - I want a lawyer.
告诉我 凯蒂
Tell me, Katie,
圣战士的妻子有什么奖励？
what are the rewards for the wife of a mujahid?
丈夫成为烈士
If one's husband becomes shahid,
妻子能得到什么？
what are the gifts bestowed upon his wife?
你的心胸太狭窄 不会懂的
Your mind is too small to understand any of this.
- 还有更多炸弹吗？- 我要律师
- Are there more bombs? - I want a lawyer.
- 不行 - 不行？
- No. - No?
- 为什么不行？- 不行
- No, what? - No.
- 我有权利 - 你什么都没有
- I have rights. - You aingt got shit, sweetheart.
- 还有更多炸弹吗？- 我被捕了吗？
- Are there more bombs? - Am I under arrest?
- 还有炸弹吗？- 我没被捕？那你们就不能拘留我
- Are there more bombs? - No? Then you can't keep me.
坐下来
Sit!
这些人是谁？
Who the fuck are these guys?
还有炸弹吗？
Are there more bombs?
你疯了 你真疯了 知道吗？
You're crazy! You're bat-shit crazy, you know that?
你脑子进水了 完全进水了
You are out of your mind. Your fucking mind.
凯蒂…
Katie...
你先生死了
your husband is gone.
他不能复生了
Forever.
亲爱的 你现在变成了寡妇
Sweetheart, you are now a widow.
你也抛弃了女儿
And have deserted your daughter,
她长大后会知道 她父亲是杀人魔
who will grow up knowing her father was a monster.
住嘴 住嘴
Stop. Stop!
他走之前 根本就没亲吻你
He didn't even kiss you before he left...
对吧？
did he?
凯蒂 为了你女儿着想
Katie, for the sake of your daughter...
还有更多炸弹吗？
are there any more bombs?
对穆斯林女人来说
For a Muslim woman,
婚姻是种矛盾
marriage is a lilting dance of duality...
强悍和服从
strength and submission.
自恋和无私
Beautiful, selfless,
两人之间轰轰烈烈的爱情
rapturous love of two masters,
肉欲和神圣
the carnal and the divine.
穆斯林女子的生活
The life a Muslim woman lives
既危险又艰苦
is a dangerous and difficult one.
如果她不服从丈夫…
If she does not submit to her husband,
死后就会下地狱
there is a spot reserved for her in Hell.
是的
Yes.
我丈夫走之前亲吻了我
My husband kissed me before he left,
我在天堂见到他时 他也会亲吻我
and he will kiss me again when I see him in Heaven.
你什么都证明不了
And you can't prove anything.
不好意思
Excuse me.
- 你觉得怎样？- 我觉得她知情
- What do you think? - I think she knew.
但你永远无法证实
But you're never gonna prove it.
就算还有炸弹 她也不会说
If there are more bombs out there, she'll never tell us.
一个母亲怎么能这么对待女儿？
How could a mother do that to her daughter?
祝好运
Good luck, huh.
你最好有重大线索
Please tell me you have something for us
时间不多 我必须做决定
because we're losing daylight and I have some decisions to make.
她什么都不说
She's not talking.
州长 我们搜寻过资料库
Mr. Governor, we ran a Guardian search.
黑帽人被列入监视名单
Black Hat was watchlisted.
我们完全忽略了他
He was right there all along, and we missed him.
这么多人力 这么多线索
All these guys. All these leads.
他是车臣人 不是盖达组织
You see a Chechen who's not AI-Qaeda,
- 甚至不是中东人 - 瑞克 别自责了
- not even Middle Eastern... - Come on, Rick. Fuck that.
我们都能检索同一个资料库
We all had access to the same database.
谁会专门去查一个自恋狂？
I mean, who was looking for some narcissistic little princess?
一个打架输了 就找人泄愤的臭小子
Some whiny little bitch who threw a tantrum because he lost a fight.
大家都发现他会殴打女友？
Everybody found out he beat up his girlfriend?
他不是烈士 他只是个孬种
He's no martyr. He's a fucking coward.
我们搜查过贝克街
We covered Barker Street.
还要搜查瓦西伯恩街
We got Washburn...
你觉得这件事能避免吗？
You think this shit is preventable?
- 避免？- 是的
- "Preventable"? - Yeah.
7年前
Seven years ago...
3月11日
on March 11th...
我们去看医生
went to the doctor.
他说我们不能生小孩
Said we couldn't have any kids.
卡萝不能生小孩
Carol couldn't have any babies.
天啊 我都不知道
Jesus, Tommy. I didn't know that.
我记得之后我们回家
I remember after, right after, we went home,
停好车 你不会想到的
parked the car in the driveway, and you don't make this kinda stuff up,
那儿有几个穆斯林小孩
right there, the Mulaney kids.
三个小女孩在玩跳房子
Three little girls out there playing hopscotch.
5岁大的小女孩
Little five-year-old girls.
我们就那么静静地看着她们
I don't know, we just sat there dead quiet watching 'em play.
- 我们就像在做梦 - 天啊
- It was like we were in a trance. - Jesus.
卡萝发出的声音…不是哭声
Sound that Carol made, it wasn't crying.
而是低低的啜泣
It was deeper.
那种声音 已不能用哭来形容
No, crying does not describe that kinda sound.
我看到她的眼神 不是痛苦
I looked into her eyes, and it wasn't pain.
而是斗志
More like war.
在她眼中 仿佛在进行一场善恶之争
Like a war between good and evil right there in her eyes.
她受到魔鬼攻击 上帝在她心里反击
Like the devil attacked, and God was inside of her fighting back.
我们会罩着你
We got your back.
我抱着她
I just held her.
我还能做什么呢？
What could I do? You know?
这也是我今天看到的
That's all I saw today.
善与恶 爱与恨
Good versus evil, love versus hate.
当魔鬼来袭…
The devil hits you like that,
只有一种武器能击败他
there's only one weapon you have to fight back with.
那就是爱
It's love.
他无法撼动爱的力量
That's the only thing he can't touch.
我们想干什么？我们抓到他们
What are we gonna do? We hunt 'em down.
抓住他们 杀死他们 然后呢？
Catch them, kill them, all that?
他们还是会攻击我们
Still gonna get us.
这种事不可能完全避免
No way it can ever be entirely preventable.
我们只能手牵手 肩并肩
Wrap our arms around each other.
让爱赐予我们力量和养分
Let love power us, feed us.
我不认为 他们最后会得到胜利
I don't think there's any way that they could ever win.
我一向都知道 你的内心深处…
I always knew there was a thing of beauty
拥有一颗美好的心肠
buried deep in the holy soul of Tommy Saunders.
我们四天前
Four days ago,
站在一个孩子的尸体前面
you and I stood over the body of a dead kid.
我们不能一无所获地 回到他家人面前
We can't go back to all those families with nothing.
我们欠他们一个交代
We owe 'em better.
马拉松上我会比你领衔
Bet I'll run the Marathon before you.
比你领"先"
It's "befo' you."
Before you.
"先"是第一声
"Befo' you." The "R" is silent.
领先
Befo' you.
上午6:35
爆炸后100小时
老婆 我出去抽根烟
Honey, I'm gonna have a smoke.
- 我就在外面 - 不行 快进来
- Just gonna be right here, okay? - No, no, come on.
来 进来
Come on, get your foot in. Get your foot in.
滑轮掉到船身外面
The roller's outta the hull.
- 没关系 - 它松掉了
- It's okay. - Came loose from the cover.
- 它会弄坏船身 - 进来吧
- It's gonna ruin the hull. - Come on.
只要一会儿就行了
It'll just take me one second, okay?
- 我出去修好他们 - 会向你开枪
- I'm just gonna run out and fix it. - They'll shoot you!
你不能出去
You're not allowed to be out there!
长官 我接到一通电话
Sir! I just got a call.
有人看到可疑人物 躲在一艘船上
Someone thinks they saw someone suspicious hide in a boat down the street.
- 一艘船？- 是船
- In a boat? - A boat.
汤米
Hey, Tommy!
- 什么情况？- 他躲在一艘船上
- What you got? What's up? - He's in the boat.
- 什么？- 他在船里
- What? - He's in the boat.
有人在我的船上
There's someone in my boat.
你的船在哪里？
There's someone in your boat? Where's the boat?
就在后面
My boat's right around back.
船罩底下有小滑轮
It's got little rollers that go underneath the cover,
- 滑轮松掉了 - 通报吧
- and the rollers came off. - Go ahead, call it in.
我是 洋基 T3小组
This is Yankee T-3.
嫌犯可能躲在法兰克街的一艘船上
We have a possible individual in a boat at 67 Franklin.
- 你家有地下室吗？- 有
- Hey, you got a basement? - Yes.
回到屋里 全家都躲进地下室
Go in the house, get your family in the basement, do not move.
慢慢来 汤米
Easy, Tommy. Easy.
该死 该死
Fuck! Fuck!
- 天哪 - 什么情况？
- Jesus. - What do you got?
- 叫他们闭嘴 - 搞什么？
- Shut them the fuck up! - What the fuck?
他在里头 他在船上
It's him. He's in there. He's in the fucking boat.
他可能会炸了那艘船 快点
It could be rigged to fucking blow! Let's go!
- 我们得逮到他 - 快回去
- We're gonna get him! - Guys, guys, get back.
- 回到车上 - 该死
- Get back in your vehicles. - Fuck, fuck, fuck.
封锁街道 清空那些房子
Secure the street! Clear these fucking houses!
我是 洋基 T3小组
This is Yankee T-3.
快派拆弹小组到法兰克街67号
We need an EOD and a tac team at 67 Franklin.
嫌犯可能躲在后院的小艇里
We got a possible suspect in the backyard in a boat.
他可能有炸弹
He may have a bomb.
撤退 让拆弹小组干活
Stand down and let the tactical unit do their job.
听得到吗？你用哪个频率？
Hey! Hey! You getting me? What frequency are you on?
- 我听不到 - 什么？
- Nah, I don't hear ya. - What?
全州的警察都来了
The whole state's fucking here, Tommy.
大家都用不同的频率
And everyone's on a different frequency.
大伙儿 无线电管制
Guys, radio discipline, please!
别出声 退后
Stay off the air. Hold back, please.
- 他在动 - 有动静
- He's moving! - Movement!
停火！
Hold your fire!
老天爷
Jesus Christ!
把武器放下
Guys, lower your weapons. Everyone.
可恶
Shit.
我说 那艘小艇又不会漂走
I'll tell ya, that boat aingt gonna float.
如果你是刚转到本台
If you're just tuning in right now,
看来追捕已经取得重大进展
there has been what appears to be
追捕行动已经展开了19个小时
a major development in what has been a 19-hour search
马拉松爆炸案嫌犯
for a 19-year-old bombing suspect
只有19岁
for the Marathon bombing.
整个场面一片混乱
And it has turned into just absolute mayhem.
该做个了断了
It's time to end this.
州警和市警立刻撤退
All state and local units stand down immediately.
让联邦调查局人质拯救队接手
FBI Hostage Rescue will be taking over.
准备攻坚
All right, let's get striking.
大家各就各位
let's move everybody into position.
这里安全
We 're clear out here.
- 你们是谁？- 我们是联邦探员
- Who the fuck are you? - Ma'am, we're with the FBI.
你们可以离开 我们来接手
You can go ahead and step down now. We got this.
波士顿联邦探员？
The FBI? Boston FBI?
不是 我们来自匡堤科
No, ma'am. We're from Quantico.
我来自马州弗雷明翰
Well, I'm from Framingham, Massachusetts,
这是我的位置 我死也不走
and this is my spot, and I aingt fucking leaving.
很高兴有你协助
Glad to have you with us, ma'am.
报告 我瞄准小艇了
Victor 4-4, Victor 1-1, I got the boat.
我们瞄着小艇
We have the boat.
Baseline green. We got the boat.
发射几枚40厘米闪光弹
run a few rounds of 40 Mike bang in there,
吓一吓这臭小子
try to shake this fellow up a little bit.
女士 这会很大声
Excuse me, ma'am. This is about to get pretty loud.
老娘才不怕
I don't give a fuck!
出来吧
Come on out!
乔卡 出来吧
Come on, Dzhokhar! Let's go!
嫌犯有动作
Okay, we have movement. We have movement.
他的手在动
Arm's moving.
我们逮到嫌犯了
Victor 3-6. One in custody.
好耶！
Yeah!
警方逮捕了19岁的乔卡沙尼耶夫
Police took 19-year-old Dzhokhar Tsarnaev into custody.
嫌犯被捕 活捉
Dangerous, as we saw. They got him alive.
大家都松了一大口气
There is a great sense of relief.
这真是好消息
This is something.
群众正在庆祝…
A crowd celebrating the news of
波士顿马拉松爆炸案
the arrest of suspect number two
第二名嫌犯被捕
in the Boston Marathon bombing.
加油 波士顿！
Let's go, Boston!
我们在此感谢民众…
We have to thank, definitely, the public for the tips
向警方提供的线索和协助
and the help and the information that we've gotten from them...
不仅仅要悼念
谢谢你 你是最棒的
Thank you. You're the best to ever wear that uniform.
好耶 波士顿
All right, Boston!
我们今天穿的球衣上面
This jersey that we wear today,
写的不是红袜队
it doesn't say "Red Sox."
而是波士顿
It say "Boston."
我们想感谢曼尼诺市长
We wanna thank you, Mayor Menino...
汤玛斯 曼尼诺
波士顿市长
派屈克州长
Governor Patrick...
德瓦 尔派屈克
马萨诸塞州州长
艾德 戴维斯
所有的警察
the whole police department...
波士顿警察局长
艾德 狄佛
水镇警局局长
这一周以来辛勤的工作
for the great job that they did this past week.
瑞克 德洛里耶斯
FBI特别探员
比利 艾文斯
波士顿警局总警监
这是我们的城市
This is our fucking city.
没有人能夺走我们的自由
And nobody gonna dictate our freedom.
我们要坚强！
Stay strong!
乔卡沙尼耶夫 被判30项罪名成立
并被判处 注射死刑
他目前囚禁于联邦监狱 等待上诉
他的三名同学 因妨碍调查罪名入狱
执法单位仍在寻找…
凯瑟琳涉及马拉松爆炸案的线索
她仍保有女儿的监护权
这两个人花了很长时间 谋划仇恨行动
Two people took many days and weeks to plan out hate.
但是民众立刻以大爱回应
But love responded in an instant.
这场大爆炸
The bombs went off and wreaked incredible havoc,
派屈克 道恩斯
洁丝 卡肯斯基
损失惨重
death, and destruction.
但是爆炸发生之后…
But in that immediate instant afterward,
人们马上就前来帮助我们
people ran toward us.
我第一次听到 坚强波士顿
I first heard the term "Boston Strong"
艾德戴维斯 前波士顿警察局长
是在调查进行两天以后
about two days into the investigation.
对我来说 那代表了…
And for me, it was emblematic of
这座城市和市民的坚韧
how tough the city and its residents can be.
我是个爱国者 我相信美国
I'm a true patriot. I really do believe in America.
坚强波士顿 这个口号代表…
And I think Boston Strong, it just shows that
我们会挺身而出 捍卫自己
we're gonna stand up and defend ourselves.
我们不会任由欺侮 被人打倒
We're not gonna take it and be beaten down.
杰夫普格列斯警长 水镇警员
我们不会打扰你
We're not gonna bother you,
但别来惹我们 我们一定会反击
but don't come at us because we're gonna come back at ya.
你们几时看到过
When's the last time you saw crowds of people
民众像这样为警察欢呼？
cheering the police on like that?
这真的让我热泪盈眶
That brought tears to my eyes. It really did.
逮到他的时候 那感觉太棒了
When we captured him, it was the best feeling in the world.
那是我身为警察以来 最棒的时刻
As a police officer, I don't ever remember having a better feeling.
比利艾文斯 波士顿警察局长
就像是打了胜仗
It's almost like we just won the war.
爆炸案发生后的一星期…
In the weeks after the bombings,
当我有机会拜访…
when I had the opportunity to visit many of the most
瑞克德洛里耶斯 联邦调查局特别探员 波士顿分局
爆炸案伤势最重的生还者
severely injured Boston Marathon bombing survivors,
我对他们展现的坚强勇气
I was absolutely amazed by the strength and resiliency
以及无比的坚强 感到非常钦佩
of the human spirit exhibited in these individuals.
真是不可思议
It was absolutely amazing.
那一天在波尔斯顿街…
I think that day on Boylston Street,
炸弹客夺走了宝贵的生命
the bombers took lives and limbs...
德瓦尔派屈克 前马萨诸塞州州长
也夺走了我们的安全感
they took some of our sense of security,
但他们夺走的没那么多
but they took a lot less than they intended.
他们给我们的东西 是他们始料未及的
And they gave us back some things they didn't intend us.
那就是团结力量和共同目标
They gave us a stronger sense of community, of common cause.
我们在世界各地都看到相同的例子
And I think we've seen that in other examples around the world.
当我们看到其它的恐怖袭击
When we see the news that another attack has happened,
布鲁塞尔…伊斯兰玛巴德…尼斯…
in Brussels, Islamabad, Nice,
奥兰多…圣贝纳迪诺…巴黎…
Orlando, San Bernardino, Paris...
最重要的是 我们不能把那些人…
I think it's important we think about these people around the world
视为暴力行为的受害者 而是视为和平大使
not as victims of violence, but ambassadors for peace.
我爱这个城市
每当我们面对挑战和困难
我们都一起面对
我们永远都怀抱着希望
坚信善良 一定会击败邪恶
我很乐观
You know, I have a tremendous amount of optimism
史提夫 安珀伍芬顿
对未来充满了希望
and hope for the future.
我希望李欧在成长过程中
Going forward with Leo,
以开放的心胸看待世界
I hope that he views the world with open eyes,
带着好奇 带着幽默感
lots of questions, and a sense of humor.
这是我们人生的最低潮
This has been the absolute worst and lowest time in our lives,
但也是最好的时刻
as well as the best.
杰西卡 肯斯基
这么说也许很怪
As bizarre as that is to say,
我不是不想念我的腿
and not that I don't miss my legs,
我每天都很想念
I miss them every day,
但是我在受到这么多的…
but after being the recipients
善意与关怀之后
of such incredible care and kindness,
我能做的就是 每天努力生活
the very least I can do is get out of bed and try again.
试着让这世界变得更美好
And try to make this world a little bit better for somebody else.
爆炸案发生后两年
About two years after the bombing,
我装了跑步义肢开始练跑
I got a running leg and started to practice with it.
但我没觉得能跑到终点
But I still didn't know I could get to the finish line
直到我们转到波尔斯顿街
until we took the turn onto Boylston.
那是最艰辛的一段路
That was the hardest stretch of the race
因为我们必须经过那里
because it was running past the spot
此处改变了我们人生
where a bomb had gone off and changed our lives,
夺走三条人命
took the lives of three others.
派屈克道恩斯过来了
And here comes Patrick Downes.
派屈克道恩斯 于2013年失去一条腿
Patrick Downes, who lost a leg in 2013,
他的太太在终点迎接他
met by his wife, Jessica Kensky.
这真是感人肺腑 激励人心的一刻
There are great moments. There are inspiring moments.
也是值得永远珍惜的一刻
There are moments to savor and treasure.
克莉丝托坎贝尔 1983-2013
吕令子 1989-2013
警官 恩柯利尔 1986-2013
马丁李察 2004-2013
谨以本片 献给所有伤者
第一时间赶到现场的医疗人员
以及所有的执法人员
他们在2013年4月发生的悲剧事件中
展现出无比的 勇气 爱心 贡献
∮All of my dreams seem to fall by the side ∮
∮Like a discarded thought or the day's fading light ∮
∮But I know that if I could just see you tonight ∮
∮Forever ∮
∮At times we may fall, like we all tend to do ∮
∮But I'll reach out and find that I've run into you ∮
∮Your strength is the power that carried me through ∮
∮Forever ∮
∮Your kindness for weakness I never mistook ∮
∮I worried you often, yet you understood ∮
∮This life is so fleeting, these troubles won't last ∮
∮Forever ∮
∮Inspired me truly, you did from the start ∮
∮To not be afraid and to follow my heart ∮
∮There's a piece of you with me they can't tear apart ∮
∮Forever ∮
∮At times we may fall ∮
∮Like we all tend to do ∮
∮Your strength is the power ∮
∮That carried me through ∮
∮Forever ∮
∮Forever I'll find you, forever we'll be ∮
∮Forever your power and strength stays with me ∮
∮Forever ∮